《屋頂人》
本影視由米奇爸爸
基於官方英文字幕翻譯製作
翡翠 你去打掃一下洗手間
Jade, I need you to start on the bathrooms.
喬斯琳 請把所有的雞蛋 麵糊
Joslyn, can you please take out all the eggs, batter,
肉餅和麥滿分從冷凍櫃裏拿出來好嗎
patties and McMuffins out of the freezer, okay?
我啟動好所有設備就來幫你
I'll help you once I turn everything on.
大家早上好
Good morning, team.
不不不
No, no, no.
別害怕
Don't be scared.
你們照我說的做 就不會有人受傷 好嗎
You just do what I say, no one gets hurt, okay?
不不 看好了
No, no, look.
槍口朝下
Pointing it down.
好了 現在我會禮貌又愉快地說聲早上好
Okay, now, I'm gonna say a polite
然後你們要回應我
and cheerful "Good morning," and then you guys say it back.
早上好
Good morning.
不對 杜安 要等我說完
No... Duane, after I say it.
規矩是這樣的 懂了嗎
That's how that works. Okay?
現在 大家早上好
Now, good morning, team.
早上好
Good morning.
沒錯 完美
Yes. Perfect.
我說什麼你們就做什麼 好了
I say what to do and you guys just do it. Okay.
我要你們把外套穿回去
I want you to get your coats back on.
杜安 拿上你的外套
Duane, grab your coat.
聽見沒 拿上你的外套
Huh? Grab your coat.
先生 我沒有外套
I don't have one, sir.
你沒有外套 你怎麼會沒有外套
You don't have a coat? How do you not have a coat?
我只是忘了帶
I just forgot.
那你今天只能挨點凍了
Well, you're just gonna have to be a little cold today.
好了 我們走
All right, let's go.
您先請 女士優先
After you. Ladies first.
聽我說
Now, listen to me.
你們不會死在這裏的
You guys aren't gonna die in here.
我一離開這裏就會報警
Soon as I'm out of here, I'm gonna call the cops
警察會來放你們出去的
and they're gonna let you guys out.
說不定還能放一天假
Probably get the day off.
不 別 別這樣
No, don't, don't.
別用那種眼神看著我
Do not look at me like that.
杜安 住手
Duane, stop it.
這都怪你
'Cause this is your fault.
好冷
It's cold.
你是認真的嗎
Are you serious?
該死
Dang it.
我真不知道是哪種混蛋
I don't know what kind of jerk
上班連自己的外套都不帶
doesn't bring his own coat to work.
好了 這下滿意了吧
Okay? Happy now?
我耳朵冷
My ears are cold.
故事的這一部分
This is the part of the story
我希望你在好奇
where I hope you're wondering
像我這樣的好人怎麼會淪為罪犯
how a nice guy like me ends up becoming a criminal.
喂
Hello?
這東西開著嗎
This thing on?
喂
Hello?
靠
Shit!
加油 杜安
Come on, Duane.
早上好 歡迎光臨麥當勞
Good morning. Uh, welcome to McDonald's.
我幫你短暫保留一下
I'm gonna put you on a brief hold.
搞什麼鬼 杜安
What the hell, Duane?
我不能怪我的父母
I can't blame my parents.
我的童年很幸福
I had a good childhood.
我只是不擅長學習和守規矩
I was just never good at school or behaving.
但我擅長某些事情
But I was good at certain things
這些事對軍隊來說很有價值
that were really valuable to the military.
但在我退伍之後
But after my discharge,
我不知道自己該何去何從 也不知道該做什麼
I didn't know where I fit or what to do
或者如何給我的孩子其他孩子擁有的東西
or how to give my kids the things that other kids had.
所以我做了一些錯誤的選擇 導致失去了其他選擇
So I made some bad choices that took away some other choices.
那些錯誤的選擇都始於兩年前
And those bad choices all started two years ago
在我女兒六歲生日派對上
at my daughter's sixth birthday party.
好了 你要許一個大大的願望
All right, you got to make a big ol' wish.
再吹一次
One more.
你許願了嗎 許了什麼願
Did you make a wish? What'd you wish for?
一輛自行車 自行車
A bike. Bike?
我不知道自行車能不能正好裝進
I don't know if a bike is exactly gonna fit
這個盒子裏 但是 撕開吧
into this box, but... rip it open.
我要跟你比賽 好啊
I'm gonna race ya. Yeah.
你覺得怎麼樣
What do you think?
很酷吧 這是我的老式工程套裝
It's cool, right? It's my old Erector Set.
我們打開吧
Let's open it up.
這裏面有200個零件
There's 200 pieces in here.
不
No!
裏面有發動機 齒輪 滑輪
I mean, you got engines, you got gears, pulleys,
輪子 燈 開關
wheels, lights, switches.
我們幾乎可以用它做出任何想要的東西
We can make almost anything that we want with this thing.
看 任何你能夢想的東西 我們都能做出來 好嗎
Look, anything that you can dream, we can make it, okay?
就你和我 你覺得怎麼樣
Me and you. What do you say?
你能用它做一輛自行車嗎
Can you make a bike with it?
能
Yeah.
我簡直不敢相信我認識的那個82師弟兄
I can't believe the dude I knew
連一輛自行車都買不起
from the 82nd can't even afford a bike.
那你告訴我你怎麼混得這麼好
Well, tell me how you're doing so well.
讓我想想
Well, let me see.
就這周 我幫兩個日本人搞到了護照
Just this week, I got two Japanese dudes passports.
每本五千塊
That's 5K a pop.
五千塊買假護照
Five grand for fake passports?
不 是真護照 老兄
No, for real passports. Man...
需要我幫忙嗎
Can I help you with that?
幫他媽個屁 你幫不了
Hell motherfucking no, you can't.
你什麼忙也幫不上
You can't help me with shit.
你瘋了嗎 老兄
You crazy, man?
你他媽什麼都幫不了我
You ain't helping me do a goddamn thing.
我不需要你幫忙
I don't need your help.
而且 我們都知道循規蹈矩
Plus, we already know that doing things the right way
不是你的強項
is not your superpower.
隨便吧 那是
Whatever. That's...
好啊 那你說我的強項是什麼
Okay, then tell me what my superpower is, then?
啟發我一下啊 佛陀 嗯
Enlighten me, Buddha. Mm.
那條水管的流速是多少
What's the flow rate on that hose?
每分鐘12加侖 嗯哼
12 gallons per minute. Mm-hmm.
這條街上有多少棟房子
How many houses is on this street?
28棟
Twenty-eight.
其中有煙囪的有多少
And out of those, how many got chimneys?
有車庫的呢
Garages?
有多少家用熱泵而不是傳統空調
How many of 'em use a heat pump instead of a traditional AC?
你想讓我推銷暖通空調系統嗎 還是
You want me to sell HVAC systems or something? Just...
不 不 老兄 我想說明一個觀點
No, no, man, I'm trying to make a point.
那就請說重點
Then make the point, please.
觀察力
Observation.
細節
Details.
你能看到別人看不到的東西
You see shit people don't see.
你就像有某種X光視覺一樣
You got like a little X-ray vision going on.
你以為他們把你扔到中美洲是因為你槍法准嗎
What, you think they dropped you off in Central America 'cause you a good shot?
你是這麼想的嗎 不 不
Is that what you think? No. No...
不 他們派你去是因為你的洞察力
No, they dropped you because of what you see.
媽的 如果我有你這樣的腦子
Shit, if I had a brain like yours,
我他媽早就統治整個世界了
I'd be running the whole goddamn world.
你知道嗎 你是我見過最聰明的傻逼黑鬼
You know, you the smartest dumb nigga I ever known.
真他媽離譜
That shit crazy.
你現在可以關掉泳池注水了
You can stop filling up that pool now.
沒人會進去的
Ain't nobody gonna get in there.
水他媽冷死了
That shit cold as hell.
所以 媽媽可能會想知道
So, Mama is probably gonna want to know
派對辦得怎麼樣 是的 我覺得我們盡力了
how the party was, and, yeah, I think we did our best.
你覺得呢
What do you think?
也許我們別提泳池的事
Maybe we don't mention the pool.
重要的是努力嘗試了 對吧
It's the trying that counts, right?
媽媽
Mommy!
嗨 壽星女
Hi, birthday girl.
你的派對怎麼樣
How was your party?
大家都盡力了
Everybody did their best.
哦 你準備好參加另一個派對了嗎
Oh. Are you ready for your other party?
嗨
Hi.
你好嗎
How are you?
嘿 我能跟你聊一下嗎
Hey, can I talk to you for a second?
很快 真的很快 很快
Real-real quick, real quick.
我知道最近幾個月不容易
I know the last few months haven't been easy,
我們連真正需要的東西都沒有
and we don't have the things that we actually need,
這都是我的錯 我承認
and that's my fault and I own that.
好嗎 我真的承認 但 但我覺得我現在有辦法了
Okay? I do, but I-I think I have it figured out now.
我只需要運用我的超能力
I just got to use my superpower and
把腦子用在想要的東西上 你的超能力
put my brain on what I want. Your superpower?
你的超能力 是的
Your superpower? Yes.
我受不了了 傑夫 聽著 不
I can't do this, Jeff. Look... No.
我受夠了 拜託別這樣
I'm done. Come on, please don't do this.
再見
Goodbye.
好了 香蕉腦袋
All right, banana head.
說再見
Say goodbye.
愛你
Love you!
等等 等等 等等 等等 等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
我不怪她嘲笑我
I didn't blame her for laughing at me.
覺得我是個笑話
For thinking I was a joke.
但她有一些關於我的事情不知道
But there were things that she didn't know about me.
一些不那麼好笑的事情
Things that weren't so funny.
史蒂夫知道我的能耐
Steve knew what I was capable of.
我確實能看到別人看不到的東西
I do see things that other people don't see.
就像現在 我看到那個孩子爬上那個梯子
Like right now, I see that kid climbing up that ladder,
我知道在那脆弱的屋頂下
and I know that under that flimsy roof
有一台能把碎牛肉和土豆變成錢的機器
is a machine that turns ground beef and potatoes into money.
有著同樣的餐廳
With the same dining room,
同樣的油炸鍋 閃爍著紅色的定時器燈
the same deep fryers with blinking red timer lights,
同樣的奶昔機 只有兩種口味
the same shake machine with the same two flavors
以及同樣的保險箱 裝滿週末的公司漢堡收入
and the same safe full of weekend corporate burger money
沒人會惦記的錢
that no one was gonna miss.
他們在完全相同的時間清空那個保險箱
They empty that safe at the exact same time
在每個週一早上 每家麥當勞都是如此
on Monday morning at every single McDonald's.
你好 歡迎光臨麥當勞
Hi. Welcome to McDonald's.
你想好要點什麼了嗎
Do you know what you want?
嗯
Huh?
嗯 嗯 嗯
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
嗯 嗯 我想好了
Um, yeah, I figured it out.
謝謝
Thank you.
全美有超過一萬家
There are over 10,000
幾乎一模一樣的麥當勞
almost identical McDonald's across the United States.
問題是 你需要搶劫多少家
Question was: How many do you need to rob
才能買到一棟真正的房子
to get a real house,
給你的孩子買好東西 贏回你的家庭
buy your kids nice things and win your family back?
結果答案是 45家
Turns out, the answer is 45.
屋頂人再次作案
The Roofman has struck again,
他在費耶特維爾麥迪遜街和朱厄爾街拐角的這家麥當勞
cutting a hole through the roof of this McDonald's
屋頂上切了一個洞
at the corner of Madison and Jewell in Fayetteville.
可想而知 這是一次可怕的經歷
As you can imagine, this was a terrifying experience.
他進來後 把我們扔進冷凍庫
He came in, threw us in the freezer
並把他的外套給了我
and gave me his coat.
他把他的外套給了你 是的
He gave you his coat? Yes.
嗯 是的 他不想讓我凍著
Uh, yeah, he didn't want me to be cold.
他其實人挺好的
He was actually really nice.
警方認為 這是同一名嫌疑人
Police believe this is the same suspect
他一直恐嚇著我們當地社區
who has been terrorizing our local community
發生了45起事件
with 45 incidents...
嗯 僅過去一年就
Mm. ...This past year alone.
我們有一張屋頂人的素描畫像
We have a sketch of the Roofman.
他總是戴著面具
He is always wearing a mask.
他被描述為身高六尺二寸 體格健壯
He's described as six-foot-two with an athletic build.
什麼 屋頂人還襲擊了
What? The Roofman has also struck.
漢堡王 肯德基
Burger King, Kentucky Fried Chicken...
這電視不錯啊 傑夫
Nice TV you got here, Jeff.
真大
Big.
你怎麼買得起這種東西
How you afford something like that?
外面有15個餓著肚子的孩子
We got 15 hungry kids out there
都快為蛋糕瘋掉了
that are losing their minds for cake.
我們得走了
We got to go.
所有這些猖獗的事件
...all of these brazen incidents...
我們得走了 等等 等等
We got to go. Hold on, hold on.
我們現在就得走 讓我看看
We got to go right now. Let me see...
如果她現在不拿到禮物
If she doesn't get her presents right now...
我想知道那個該死的嫌疑人到底怎麼回事
I want to know what's going on with the damn suspect.
她會發瘋的 我能看看嗎
she's gonna lose her mind. Can I see?
好了 你為什麼關掉
All right. Why you turning it off?
等等 等等 等等 等等 別 別 別
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. Don't, don't, don't, d...
快點
Come on.
走吧
Let's go.
真他媽該死
Goddamn, man.
祝你生日快樂
Happy birthday to you
祝你
Happy birthday
生日快樂
To you
生日快樂 親愛的
Happy birthday, bandida
祝你生日快樂 你
Happy birthday to you You.
開始吧
Let's go!
好了
All right.
深吸一口氣 許個大願 來吧
Big breath, big wish. Here we go.
好了 今年我們先拆這個
All right, we're gonna do this one first this year.
小盒子裏裝大東西
Big things in little boxes.
這是什麼
What is this?
車庫門遙控器
A garage door opener?
你為什麼給我一個車庫門遙控器
Why'd you give me a garage door opener?
我不知道 我只是想不出別的地方
I don't know. I just couldn't think of anywhere else
來放 呃 那只劍齒虎 所以
to put, uh, the saber-toothed tiger, so...
我不知道 我不能把它放在廚房 對吧
I couldn't put it in the kitchen, could I?
那它在哪兒
So, where is it?
你是全世界最棒的爸爸
You're the best daddy in the whole entire world!
好了 快上去試試
Now, go ahead, get on it.
我太喜歡了
I love it.
你們好嗎
How you guys doing?
我們找傑弗裏·曼徹斯特
We're looking for Jeffrey Manchester.
是關於車輛登記的事嗎
This about the registration?
是的 我正好放在這裏面 稍等
Yeah, I got it right in here. One second.
別動
Stop.
你被逮捕了
You're under arrest!
哇 嘿 嘿 嘿
Whoa! Hey, hey, hey.
不許動 你被逮捕了
Freeze! You're under arrest!
曼徹斯特先生 請起立
Mr. Manchester, please rise.
州政府已超越合理懷疑標準證明
The State has proved beyond the defined burden
你犯下了持危險武器搶劫罪
that you committed the crime of robbery with a dangerous weapon.
我希望能考慮到
I'd like to take in consideration
你曾在我國武裝部隊中服役
your service to this country in the armed forces
以及你的孩子失去父親的影響
and the impact of your children losing a father.
我知道你騙過了所有人
Now, I know you got everyone fooled
以為你是個好人 但我知道你是個禍害
thinking you're a nice guy, but I know you're a menace.
雖然你只因一次搶劫受審
Although you're only being tried for one robbery,
但我們知道你作案遠不止於此
we know you've done many more.
因此檢方要求
And so the prosecution has requested
我對你鎖在冷凍庫裏的每一位受害者
that I issue a single count of felony kidnapping
各判一項重罪綁架罪
for each victim you locked in the freezer.
記錄在案 2004年2月4日
Let the record state that on the 4th of February, 2004,
你特此被判每項罪名180個月
you're hereby sentenced to 180 months
三名受害者共計
for each of the three victims,
總計540個月 即45年
for a total of 540 months or 45 years
在北卡羅來納州懲教署服刑
in the North Carolina Department of Corrections.
警長先生 他交由你羈押
Mr. Sheriff, he is in your custody.
本案審理結束
This concludes this case.
嗨 爸爸
Hi, Daddy.
我好想你
I really missed you.
我也想你 非常想你
Miss you, too. I miss you a lot.
嘿 你收到我畫的那張大房子的信了嗎
Hey, did you get the letter that I drew the big ol' house on it?
沒有
No.
嗯 可能還沒寄到 問問媽媽
Well, maybe it hasn't arrived. Ask Mama.
媽媽說她會把信收起來
Mom says she'll save the letters.
等我長大了 就可以看了
When I'm old enough, I can read them.
不 不 這樣不對 這樣不對
No, no. That is not... that is not right.
這些信是 是給現在看的
These letters are for, they're for right now.
告訴他我們要切斷聯繫了
Tell him we're cutting the cord.
他們說我們必須切斷聯繫
They said we have to cut the cord.
不 我們不會切斷聯繫的
No, we're not cutting the cord.
誰說的
Who said that?
我們參加了一個為父親在監獄的家庭舉辦的會議
We went to a meeting for families with dads in prison.
好吧 那是好事
Okay, well, that's good.
那真的很好 他們在那裏說了什麼
That's really good. What'd they say there?
說這不是我的錯 是你的錯
That it isn't my fault. It's your fault.
要徹底地放手
And to let you go, all the way,
因為你永遠不會回家 即使你說你會
'cause you'll never come home, even if you say you will.
聽著 最後那部分不對 那是非常非常錯誤的
Look, that last part is not... that is very, very wrong.
剩餘60秒
You have 60 seconds remaining.
嘿 能讓你媽媽聽一下電話嗎
Hey, can you put your mom on for a second?
他想和你說話
He wants to talk to you.
不 告訴他你得掛電話了
No. Tell him that you have to hang up.
加裏會幫你輔導作業
Gary's gonna help you with your homework.
她不想和你說話
She doesn't want to talk to you.
她說我得掛電話去做作業了
She said I have to get off and do homework.
加裏會幫我
Gary is going to help me.
加裏 加裏是誰
Gary? Who's Gary?
媽媽的朋友
Mom's friend.
哈 媽媽有個新朋友叫加裏
Huh. Mom's got a new friend named Gary.
那 那挺有意思
That's-that's fun.
沒關係 寶貝 你可以告訴他
It's okay, sweetheart. You can tell him.
嗯 好吧 我明天老時間再打給你
Um, okay, I'm gonna call you tomorrow at the same time
我每次都這樣 好嗎
I always do, all right?
他們說不能再打電話了
They said no more calls.
不 不 誰說的 不
No, no. Who said that? No.
掛電話吧
Hang up the phone.
沒關係 貝姬
It's okay, Becky.
你現在可以掛了 掛電話
You can hang up now. Hang up?
是加裏嗎 讓他接電話 馬上
Is that Gary? Put him on the phone right now.
掛掉 掛掉
Hang up. Hang up.
讓加裏或者你媽媽接電話 馬上 貝姬 好嗎
Put Gary or your mom on the phone right now, Becky, okay?
我得掛電話了 嘿
I have to hang up. Hey.
聽我說 我會回家的
Listen to me, I'm coming home.
告訴你的兄弟們我會回家的
Tell your brothers I'm coming home.
我們不說再見 因為再見意味著離開
And we don't say goodbye, 'cause goodbye means going away
離開意味著遺忘 而我們
and going away means forgetting, and we're...
我們 喂
We're... H-Hello?
喂
Hello?
貝 貝姬
B... Becky?
你為什麼還在想他們
Why is you still thinking about them?
你必須放下
You got to let that go.
你出不去的
Ain't no getting out of here.
把這個念頭從你腦子裏趕出去
Get that idea out your head.
每個囚犯都想要同樣的東西
Every prisoner wants the same thing:
離開監獄
to get out of prison.
他們認為出路是穿牆
And they think that the way out is through a wall
或者越獄
or over a fence.
但獄警們已經嚴防死守
But the guards got that covered.
離開監獄的途徑在於人
The way out of prison is through the people.
監獄不過是另一座建築
Prison was just another building
充滿了系統和例行程序
full of systems and routines.
保持例行程序 獄警就不會起疑
Keep the routine, and the guards won't get suspicious.
如果你足夠友善 如果你有用
If you're nice enough, if you're useful,
他們就會忘記你進來是有原因的
they forget you're in there for a reason.
當他們不再監視你
And when they stop watching you,
你就可以開始監視他們
you can start watching them.
你聞到什麼味了嗎
You smell that?
聞起來像是你在漏油
Smells like you're leaking.
幫我檢查一下怎麼樣
How 'bout checking it out for me.
好的 長官 看看有沒有什麼問題
Yes, sir. See if you see anything.
是的
Yeah.
目前看起來還不算太糟
Doesn't look too bad just yet.
我不知道 大概能撐到你回去
I don't know... it'll probably get you back to where you're going.
好了 出來吧 好的
All right. Well, come on out of there. All right.
是的 你最好告訴你的維修人員
Yeah, you better tell your maintenance guy.
你可能需要換個新墊圈
You might need a new gasket.
謝了 老兄 不客氣 長官
I appreciate it, man. Yes, sir.
祝你好運 你也是
Have a good one. You, too.
是的 直接倒車
Yeah. Straight back.
兩個箱子 是的
Two boxes.  Yep.
兩條長凳 是的 長官
Two benches. Yes, sir.
好了
All right.
熄火吧
Shut her down.
交給你了 卡明斯先生 謝謝 老弟
She's all yours, Mr. Cummings. Thank you, bud.
嘿 聞起來像是你修好了
Hey, smells like you fixed it.
發現得及時
Good catch.
好了 小心駕駛 好的 祝你順利
All right, drive safe. All right, have a good one.
天啊
Jesus.
呼
Phew.
是的
Yeah.
是的 踩油門 踩油門 踩油門 踩油門 踩油門
Yeah, pedal, pedal, pedal, pedal, pedal.
喂
Hello?
史蒂夫 是我
Steve. It's me.
傑夫 傑夫 你他媽給我打電話幹什麼 老兄
Jeff, Jeff, what the fuck are you doing calling me, man?
你他媽滿新聞都是
You all over the goddamn news and shit.
聽著 我必須離開這個國家
Look, I got to get out of the country.
我在想 比如巴西或委內瑞拉
I'm thinking, like, Brazil or Venezuela.
有海灘且沒有引渡條約的地方
Somewhere with a beach and no extradition.
天啊 你聽起來真他媽瘋了
God, you sound fucking crazy.
我知道 對不起
I know. I'm sorry.
別做傻事 比如去看你的家人
Don't do no stupid shit like go see your family.
躲起來 好嗎 好的 好的 我會躲起來
Hide. All right? Okay. Okay. I'll hide.
一個月內別再打來
Don't call back for another month.
好的 我一個月後打給你
All right, I'm-a call you in a month.
別再打我這個該死的電話了
And don't call my motherfucking phone again.
明白了嗎 好的
You got it? A'ight.
史蒂夫
Steve?
史
St...
你 很多
You.  A lot.
很多 我們有 是的 你想要什麼
A lot? We have... Yep. What do you want?
一隻猴子 猴子
A monkey. A monkey?
等一下
Wait a minute.
烏龜 烏龜
Turtle.  Turtle.
什麼 你想要什麼 糖果
What... and what do you want?  Candy.
糖果
Candy?
我們有很多糖果
We got a lot of candy.
呃 先生 我們還有十分鐘關門
Uh, um, sir, we're closing here in ten minutes.
先生 嗯 沒問題
Sir? Yeah, no problem.
我明白你的意思了
I got you.
零 三 六
Zero, three, six,
五 九 八 二
five, nine, eight, two.
洗手間沒人
Bathroom's clear.
各位請注意
Attention,
玩具反斗城的顧客們
Toys "R" Us customers.
本店將在五分鐘後關門
Our store will be closing in five minutes.
所以 如果你不是玩具或員工
So, if you are not a toy or an employee,
請將您選購的商品帶到前台
please bring your purchases up to the front.
無論您是孩子 家長
Whether you are a kid or a parent
叔叔或是幫朋友實現夢想的人
or an uncle or a friend making a dream come true,
現在是時候做出選擇
it is time to make your choices
到前面的收銀台結賬
and meet us at the register up front.
如果您今晚無法決定 別擔心
If you can't decide tonight, don't worry.
我們向您保證明天還會營業
We promise you we will be here tomorrow,
只要您向我們保證永遠不長大多好
just as long as you promise us to never grow up.
傑弗裏·曼徹斯特 也被稱為
Jeffrey Manchester, also known
屋頂人 於今天早些時候從布朗溪監獄越獄
as the Roofman, escaped from Brown Creek Prison earlier today.
今晚 他仍然在逃
Tonight, he's still out there somewhere.
當局發現了曼徹斯特
Authorities discovered Manchester,
他因持械搶劫和綁架罪正在服刑45年
who was serving 45 years for armed robbery and kidnapping,
今天下午例行點名時失蹤
was missing this afternoon...
哈 在例行點名時
Ha. during a routine head count.
懲教官員不知道曼徹斯特越獄的方法
Correction officers do not know the method
或確切時間
or exact time of Manchester's escape...
他們還不知道我是怎麼出來的
They still don't know how I got out.
但認為他可能仍在夏洛特地區
but believe he may still be in the Charlotte area.
不 不 不 我 我早就遠走高飛了 我們認為他逃走了
No, no, no. I'm-I'm long gone. We believe he fled
在今天中午12點到下午4點之間的某個時間
sometime between 12:00 and 4:00 this afternoon.
他是個非常聰明的人 超級聰明
He's a very smart individual. Super intelligent.
可能達到天才水平
Probably genius level.
但他也是個十足的傻瓜
But he's also an absolute idiot.
我們認為嫌疑人可能攜帶武器
We believe that the suspect could be armed.
並且他有暴力行為的歷史
And he has a history of violent behavior.
什麼 警方要求
What? Police are asking
如果你看到長得像曼徹斯特的人
if you see someone who looks like Manchester,
請致電當局 不要與他正面衝突
please call authorities and do not confront him.
好的
Okay.
好了
All right.
是的
Yeah.
密碼 一 二 三 四
Password: One, two, three, four,
五 六
five, six.
哇 是的
Whoa. Yeah.
大多數人
Most guys, when they escape,
越獄後幾小時內就會被抓住
get caught in the first few hours.
他們盡可能快 盡可能遠地逃跑
They go as far as they can as fast as they can.
但那從來都不管用
And that never works.
訣竅是停下來
The trick is to stop.
找一個沒人會找的地方
Find a place no one will look.
有時 最好的藏身之處就在眾目睽睽之下
Sometimes, the best hiding places are in plain sight.
一個人們都太專注於自己的事而看不到你的地方
A place where people are too preoccupied to see you.
所以我安靜得像隻老鼠
So I kept quiet as a mouse.
但不是在晚上
But not at night.
夜晚屬於我
I owned the night.
我們哪裏出了問題
Where did we go wrong?
對屋頂人的搜捕
The manhunt for the Roofman
進入第三天
enters its third day.
人們
People have short attention spans.
過一陣子他們就會覺得無聊
After a while, they get bored.
我估計我需要安靜大約一個月左右
I figured I had to be quiet for about a month, give or take.
警方對越獄犯傑弗裏·曼徹斯特的行蹤
Still no leads from police on the whereabouts
仍然沒有線索
of escaped convict Jeffrey Manchester,
搜捕行動進入第八天
as the manhunt enters its eighth day.
有一次
One time, when I was in the 82nd,
我在森林裏待了30天
I spent 30 days in the woods
靠雨水和蠐螬生存
surviving off of rainwater and grubs.
你的身體不需要太多就能維持下去
Your body doesn't need much to keep going.
你需要照顧的是你的大腦
It's your brain that you have to take care of.
如果你能讓你的大腦想像一個更好的地方
If you can make your brain imagine a better place,
它就能幫你度過任何難關
it can get you through anything.
隨便選個地方 只要不是你現在待的地方
Just pick any place but where you are.
比如海邊的沙灘
Like a beach on an ocean.
一個在你的孩子可以拜訪的地方
A place where your kids can visit
在所有人都忘記你之後
after everyone else forgets you.
將近兩周
Nearly two weeks
自從傑弗裏·曼徹斯特
since Jeffrey Manchester escaped
從布朗溪監獄越獄
from Brown Creek Penitentiary.
警方設置了路障
Police have set up roadblocks,
擔心曼徹斯特可能仍在該地區
concerned Manchester may still be in the area.
警官 我是第六頻道新聞的
Sergeant, I'm with Channel 6 News.
傑弗裏·曼徹斯特仍然在逃
Jeffrey Manchester's still missing.
你認為他可能在夏洛特嗎
Do you think he could be in Charlotte?
他可能一直在移動
He might've kept moving,
但我們不會放棄他可能仍藏匿在此地的可能性
but we're not gonna give up on the possibility
他可能仍藏匿在
that he still might be hiding out here
梅克倫堡縣
in Mecklenburg County.
當他試圖逃跑時 我們會準備好的
And when he tries to run, we'll be ready.
祝你好運
Good luck.
永遠不要相信別人
Never trust another
因為他們都想
'Cause they're all out to getcha
我們必須在這個世界上一起生活
We have to live in this world together
一起
'Gether
如果我們敞開心扉 愛終將開始
If we open up our heart, love can finally start
來吧 嘗試一下
Come on and try
就是現在
Now's the time
因為你是自由的
'Cause you're free
去做你想做的事
To do what you want to do
你必須過你自己的生活
You got to live your life
做你想做的事
Do what you want to do
Do what you want
做你想做的事
Do what you want to do
Do what you want
做你想做的事
Do what you want to do
一個小問題
One quick question.
嗯 是的
Uh, yeah.
好的 我想跟你談談我的工作時間
Okay. I just wanted to talk to you about my hours.
嗯
Um...
我每隔一個週末需要休息
I need every other weekend off.
我有點困惑
I'm confused.
你先向我要工作
First you ask me for a job,
現在又向我要休假
and now you're asking me for time off.
嗯 你知道
Well, you know,
我是個有團隊精神的人 是的
I'm a team player... Yeah.
但是 嗯 我也是個母親
but, um, I'm also a mom.
我知道
I know.
好吧 嗯 我知道
Okay. Well... I do.
呃 你 你提醒我了
Uh... You-you reminded me.
我六個月前離婚了 所以
I got a divorce six months ago, so...
現在對我來說平衡所有事情真的很難
it's really hard for me to balance everything right now
工作 我的女兒們 還有我的前夫
with work and my girls and my ex.
哦 得了吧 監護權的情況是
Oh, come on. The custody situation is:
你知道 一個週末跟他 一個週末跟我
They have, you know, one weekend him, one weekend me.
我不想用我的個人問題來煩你
I don't want to bore you with my personal problems.
很好 很好 因為我不想被你的個人問題煩到
Good, good. 'Cause I don't want to be bored by your personal problems.
如果這是玩具反斗城的問題 那我感興趣
If this is a Toys "R" Us problem, then I'm interested.
但個人問題屬於個人時間
But personal problems belong on personal time.
謝謝你 莉 我得回去處理工資單了
Thank you, Leigh. Got to get back to payroll.
工作 工作 工作 工作 工作 工作 工作
Work, work, work, work, work, work, work.
很高興見到你
Good to see you.
真是個混蛋 謝謝 米奇
What a dick. Thanks, Mitch.
好的
Okay.
難以置信
Unbelievable.
是的 你是個難以置信的混蛋
Yeah, you're an unbelievable dick.
我知道你是個母親 你之前提過
I know you're a mom. You mentioned it before.
母親牌 難以置信
Mom card. Unbelievable.
美元符號 U
Dollar sign, U,
美元符號 美元符號
dollar sign, dollar sign.
這是我聽過最蠢的密碼
That's the dumbest password I've ever...
我聽過最蠢的
I've ever heard of.
成功
"$ucce$$."
呵
Heh.
我們找到莉了
We found Leigh.
週六
Saturday.
再見
Goodbye.
嗶嗶嗶嗶嗶嗶嗶嗶嗶嗶
Boop, boop, boop, boop, boop, boop, boop, boop, boop, boop.
你現在放假了
You have the day off now.
搞定
Voila.
新聞現在開始
The news starts now.
預計有三萬多人
More than 30,000 folks are expected
涌入小鎮
to crowd into town.
想出了 美女洗車 的主意
...came up with the idea "Babe Wash."
比基尼確實帶來了生意
And the bikinis do bring in the business.
最大的獨立日慶祝活動
The biggest celebrations of the Fourth
在我身後的天空中進行
take place in the skies right behind me.
人們
People get bored
對上星期的新聞感到厭倦
with last week's news.
很快 他們甚至不記得為什麼認得你的臉了
Pretty soon, they can't even remember why they know your face.
就連警察也會失去興趣 除非你真的惹毛了他們
Even cops lose interest unless you really piss 'em off.
每個人最終都會忘記你
Everybody forgets you eventually.
除了真正愛你的人
Except people who really love you.
我現在無法接觸到愛我的人 否則會傷害他們
I couldn't get to the people who love me now without hurting them.
我唯一可能再見到他們的地方是在別處
The only place I might ever see them again was somewhere else
和別的某個時間
and some other time.
第一步是離開這裏
The first step was getting out of here...
去往那裏
to get there.
喂
Hello?
嗨 嗯
Hi. Um...
什 是 呃 我 我能和史蒂夫通話嗎
Wh... Is, uh... May I, may I speak to Steve?
請問 你是哪位
Please? Sorry, who is this?
哦 是一位朋友
Oh, this is a friend.
嗯 我是 奧利弗 他的 呃 他的表弟
Well, I mean, this is... Oliver. His, uh, his cousin.
我在 我在做一次小小的
I was... I'm doing this little...
小小的橫穿全國旅行 呃
little cross-country trip, and, uh,
他 他應該知道 我本來要去拜訪他
he was, he was expecting me. I was supposed to visit.
嗯 嗯
Mm. Mm.
他沒提過有訪客
He didn't say anything about a visit.
而且我不知道他有個表弟
And I didn't know he had a cousin.
他一定是忘了提吧 我猜
He must have forgot to mention it, I guess.
呃
Um...
我在跟誰 我在跟誰說話
Who am I sp... who am I speaking with?
哦 我是他女朋友
Oh, I'm his girlfriend.
不過這是有什麼事嗎
What is this about, though?
因為我正忙著呢 所以 呃
'Cause I'm in the middle of something, so, uh...
他的女 好吧 太好了
His girl... okay, great.
我現在能和史蒂夫通話嗎
Could I talk to Steve now?
他不在這兒
He isn't here.
好吧 那我應該 比如 過一會兒
Okay, well, should I call back in, like, a...
比如 一個小時左右再打來
like, an hour or so?
呃 他12月1號之前都不會回來
Uh, well, he's not gonna be back until December 1st.
誰會出去直到12月
Where does anyone go till December?
他在阿富汗
He's in Afghanistan.
他不在阿富汗
He's not in Afghanistan.
我們兩年前就從阿富汗回來了
We got back two years ago from Afghanistan.
嗯 他接了個六個月的合同
Well, he took a six-month contract.
呃 但他讓我幫他留口信
Um, but he asked me to take messages for him.
有什麼話想讓我
Is there something that you want me
轉告他嗎 如果他打電話來的話
to tell him if he calls?
嗯 呃
Yeah, uh...
告訴他 呃 表弟奧利弗會待在
tell him that, uh, Cousin Oliver is gonna stay
這附近的親戚家 直到他回來
with relatives in the area until he's back
在12月1號 為了一個非常重要的會面
on December 1st for a really important meeting.
好的 我會告訴他的
Okay, I will tell him that.
呃 那我到時候也會見到你吧 我猜
And, uh, I will see you then, too, I guess.
表弟奧利弗
Cousin Oliver.
再見
Bye.
喂
Hello?
別撓我癢癢 等一下
Stop tickling me. Just a sec.
喂
Hello?
加裏瘋了
Gary is crazy.
加裏
Gary!
是誰 喂
Who is it? Hello?
加裏
Gary!
喂 加裏
Hello? Gary.
你是誰
Who is this?
傑夫 是你嗎
Jeff, is this you?
如果你再打來 我就報警了
If you call here again, I'm gonna call the cops.
聽見了嗎
Do you hear me?
我們已經翻篇了
We've moved on.
你也需要翻篇了
And you need to move on, too.
別再打來了
Don't call here anymore.
好癢啊
That tickles.
哦 天哪 好癢
Oh, boy, that tickles.
艾摩想玩
Elmo wants to play.
我們來玩吧
Let's play.
哦 天哪 好癢
Oh, boy, that tickles.
艾摩愛你
Elmo love you.
艾摩想玩 你是艾摩的甜心
Elmo wants to play. You're Elmo's sweetheart.
好癢 我們來玩吧
That tickles. Let's play.
艾摩愛你
Elmo love you.
哦 天哪 好癢
Oh, boy, that tickles.
我們來玩吧
Let's play.
艾摩愛你
Elmo love you.
艾摩喜歡他的ABC
Elmo loves his ABCs...
嘿 莉 奧蒂斯奧蒂斯奧蒂斯
Hey, Leigh. Otee-Otee-Otis.
嘿
Hey.
嘿 米奇
Hey, Mitch.
你正是我想見的人
You're just the man I want to see.
酷
Cool.
你 呃
You, uh...
你喜歡花生M&M's 對吧
you like Peanut M&Ms, right?
是的 是嗎
Yeah. Yeah?
是的
Yeah.
因為我們丟了很多
'Cause we're missing a lot
花生M&M's 你知道是為什麼嗎
of Peanut M&Ms. You have any idea why?
不知道
No.
怎麼了 沒事
What's wrong? Nothing's wrong.
看起來有點緊張 我沒有
Seem nervous.  I'm not.
沒有
No.
沒有 沒有 不可能
No? No. Not happening.
你不能那樣跟他說話
You can't talk to him like that.
好吧 你知道 我們外面少了半打盒子
Okay. You know, we are missing half a dozen boxes out there.
我只是覺得 嗶
And I just thought... boop...
它們肯定藏在某個地方 嗶
they got to be hiding somewhere... boop.
我非常抱歉
I am so sorry.
天啊 他不能那樣跟你說話
Oh, God. He cannot talk to you that way.
我倒成了壞人了
I'm the bad guy now.
嘿 你必須為自己挺身而出
Hey. You got to stick up for yourself.
好嗎 否則他會變本加厲的
Okay? Or he's just gonna get worse.
我不太擅長衝突 所以
I'm not big on conflict, so...
是的 好吧 嗯 我們會 我們會改進的
Yeah. Okay, well, we'll-we'll work on that.
酷
Cool.
聽著 米奇 你真的很傷奧蒂斯的感情
Listen, Mitch, you really hurt Otis's feelings,
我認為你應該道歉
and I think you should apologize.
對不起
I'm sorry.
嗯 這是個好的開始
Well, that's a good start.
好的 你知道
Okay. You know,
人們尊重領導者的仁慈
people respect kindness in a leader.
嗯
Mm.
考慮到這一點
W-With that in mind,
我想邀請你去我的教堂
I wanted to invite you to my church.
十字路口教堂
Crossroads Church.
呃 就在州際公路對面
It's, uh, just across the interstate.
呃 你去過嗎
Uh... Have you been?
我不太去教堂
Not very churchy.
好吧 嗯 我在那裏負責玩具募捐活動
Okay, well, I'm in charge of the toy drive there,
這讓我想到 我就在這裏
and it got me thinking, here I am,
在所有地方中的一家玩具店工作
working in a toy store of all places,
而你甚至沒有捐一個玩具給我的玩具募捐活動
and you haven't even donated one toy to my toy drive.
嗯 我們在這裏是賣玩具的 不是送玩具的
Well, we sell toys here. We don't give 'em away.
好吧 那些退回的玩具呢
Okay. What about all those returned toys?
那些完好無損但我們不能賣的
Perfectly good ones that we can't sell.
我們在這裏是做生意 莉
We run a business here, Leigh.
好吧 嗯 你仍然可以來
Okay. Well, you can still come.
你知道 所有人都歡迎
You know, all people are welcome.
即使他們刻薄或者還沒準備好
Even if they're mean or aren't quite ready yet.
所以你可以來 帶一大袋玩具來 或者不帶
So you can come, bring a big bag of toys, or not.
你都會受到歡迎
You'll be welcome.
但帶上玩具 你就能當一回好人了
But bring the toys and you could be a good guy for once.
你難道不想當個好人嗎
Don't you want to be a good guy?
來吧 米奇 當個好人
Come on, Mitch! Be a good guy!
好吧
Okay.
那是垃圾嗎
Is that garbage?
呃
Uh...
嗯 需要我幫你把那扔進垃圾箱嗎
Huh? Do you want me to put that in the garbage for you?
這只是給
It's just toys for the...
呃 我聽說有個玩具募捐活動
Uh, I heard there was a toy drive.
嗯 這邊走
Well, it's right this way.
我 我就放這兒吧 沒關係
It's o... I'll just leave 'em here. It's okay.
我不想穿著這高跟鞋
I'm not gonna walk
一路走到那頭去
all the way down there in these heels.
你真好心
It's very nice of you.
給你
Here you go.
謝謝
Thank you.
哦 對我來說太重了
Oh, it's too heavy for me.
得把它搬進去
Got to bring it on in there.
來吧 我帶你看看玩具放哪兒
Come on, I'll show you where the toys go.
你想讓我放哪兒
Where do you want me to put 'em?
你可以直接搬到這裏面來
You can bring 'em right in here.
禮拜快開始了
Service is about to begin.
任何在外面感到孤獨的人
Anyone that feels alone out there...
就到這裏來
just come on down here.
因為你屬於這裏
'Cause you belong here.
我們都是罪人
We're all sinners here,
所以有時我請我妻子唱這首歌
which is why I ask my wife sometimes to sing this tune.
在絕望的時刻
In times of despair
我回想你所行的美事
I think about The good things That you've done
哦 雖然你不在那裏
Ooh, and though You're not there
我有時問自己
I sometimes ask myself
有誰在嗎 有誰在嗎
Is anyone?  Is anyone?
是的 哦
Yeah Oh
做人真難
It's so hard being human
面對所有煩惱
With all the troubles
在眼前
In sight
但不知何故我知道
But somehow I know
我知道 我知道 我知道 我知道
I know, I know, I know, I know
一切都會好起來的
Everything's gonna Work out all right
嘿 是的
Hey, yeah
但不知何故我知道
But somehow I know
一切都會好起來的
Everything's gonna Work out all right
嘿 但不知何故我知道
Hey, but somehow I know
一切都會好起來的
Everything's gonna Work out all right
哈利路亞
Hallelujah.
哇 有人餓壞了 是吧
Wow. Somebody is very hungry, huh?
胃口很大啊 是吧
Big appetite there, huh?
抱歉 請便
Sorry. Please.
我好久沒吃到這麼好吃的食物了
I haven't had food this good in so long.
不 那很好 大塊頭吃大份食物
No, that's great. Big food for a big guy.
是的 是的
Yeah. Yeah.
你可不能偷偷溜走
Now, you can't sneak out of here
不跟牧師和他妻子打個招呼
without saying hello to the pastor and his wife.
不 這是違反規定的
No. It's against the rules.
不 我絕不會 我絕不會
No, I would never. I would never.
我是艾琳
I'm Eileen.
約翰 佐 呃 佐林 約翰·佐林
John. Z... uh, Zorin. John Zorin.
我以前沒在這附近見過你
Yeah, I haven't seen you around the area before.
我注意到你了 顯然 在 在那排座位上
I noticed you, obviously, in the, in the-the row there.
你從哪裏來 是新搬到這裏的嗎
Where are you from? You new to the area?
是的 呃 我 我是
Yeah, uh, I'm-I'm...
我剛到這裏不久 真的 對所有事情都很陌生
I'm just new to this place and, really, everything.
你知道 這 呃
You know, it's, um...
所有這一切對我來說 你知道
All of this is really just, you know...
這裏每 每件事對我來說都很新鮮
Every-Everything here is just new for me.
我 我從紐約市來的
I'm-I'm down from New York City.
那是個適合步行的城市
That's a walking man's town,
如果我去過的話
I mean, if ever I've been-been to one.
那是個適合步行的城市 沒錯
That is a walking man's town. That is correct.
我猜你穿壞了很多雙運動鞋吧
I bet you go through a lot of pair of sneakers, don't you?
每個人都這樣 對吧 你穿壞了
Everyone does. Right? Do you go through...
是的 是的 哦 天啊 你
Yeah, yeah. Oh, my. You've...
你這個大個子腳可真小
You got very small feet for a big guy.
不 我腳其實很大 只是
No, I actually have large feet. It's just,
我穿錯了鞋 我不知道
I put on the wrong shoes, and I don't know,
我覺得這雙大概是女碼九號
I think these are, like, nines in women's.
對不起 我絕不會穿運動鞋來教堂的
And I'm sorry, I would never wear sneakers to church.
我 真的很抱歉
I-I'm really sorry.
你知道 我 我想介紹你認識一個人
You know, I-I would like to introduce you to someone.
我想介紹你認識莉·溫斯考特
I'd like to introduce you to Leigh Wainscott.
她負責這裏的玩具募捐
She runs the toy drive here,
我聽說你捐了非常慷慨的禮物
and I heard you gave such a generous donation.
我知道她會想感謝你的
I know she'd like to thank you for it.
你知道 她看起來有點忙 真的 艾琳
You know, she looks a bit busy over there, actually, Eileen.
她正在和她女兒嚴肅地談話
She's having a serious conversation with her daughter.
現在嗎
Now?
是的 我們可以
Yeah. We can.
是的 好的 你捐了這麼棒的禮物
Yeah. Okay. You made such a great donation.
好的 是的 當然 是的 嘿 嘿
Okay. Yeah, sure. Yeah. Hey, hey.
好的 太好了 呃 莉 嘿 莉
Okay, great. Uh, Leigh. Hey, Leigh.
莉 嘿 莉
Leigh. Hey, Leigh.
來 來跟我們的神秘先生打個招呼
Come, come say hi to our mystery man.
好的 來吧
Okay. Come on.
是的 是的
Yeah. Yeah.
這是我們的明星莉
This is our all-star Leigh.
她是這裏所有善事的骨幹
She is the backbone of everything
在這個教堂裏
that is good going on in this church.
她負責外展 提供餐食
She does the outreach, does the meals,
負責玩具募捐 她
does the toy drive, she...
我真不知道她是怎麼做到這一切的 但她做到了
I really don't know how she does it all, but she does.
這是約翰
And this is John...
佐林 佐林 從紐約來的
Zorin? Zorin from New York.
哦 紐約
Oh, New York.
離這裏很遠 是的 有點遠 是的
That's far from here. Yeah, a little bit, yeah.
所以 約翰 他捐了非常慷慨的玩具
So, John... he made a very generous toy donation.
哦 你太客氣了 我們
Oh, that's so kind of you. We...
來得正是時候
Couldn't have come at a better time.
不 我 我是說 呃 我真的很喜歡聖誕節和生日
No, I-I mean, um, I really like Christmas and-and birthdays,
呃 還有送禮物的時光
uh, and just gift-giving time.
我是說 我不知道
I mean, I don't know.
我就是喜歡孩子 你有孩子嗎 約翰
I just love kids. You have kids, John?
嗯 你有家庭嗎 還是單身
You have a family, or are you single?
我 呃 剛剛正式離婚 就這樣
I'm, uh, just officially divorced, that's all.
哦 我很遺憾 約翰
Oh, I'm sorry, John.
不是 不是所有婚姻都能成功 對吧
Not-not all marriages work out, right?
那 那是真的
That's... that is true.
但回答你的問題 我確實有孩子
But to answer your question, I do have kids.
我有兩個小淘氣男孩
I have two little monster boys,
還有一個小女兒 她是我最好的夥伴
and I got a little girl that is my best pal.
真溫馨 而且 呃 是的
That's sweet. And, um... Yeah.
但他們在紐約 我在這裏工作
But they're in New York, and I'm here working.
那 那 那你是做什麼工作的
And what-what-what do you... what do you do for work?
嗯 我 我為政府工作
Well, I... I-I work for the government,
呃 但我不能細說
um, but I can't exactly talk about it.
這 呃 這是機密
It's, uh, it's classified
之類的無聊規定 哦
and all that silliness. Oh.
嗯 來自紐約的約翰·佐林 我們的紐約間諜
Well, John Zorin from New York, our New York spy.
不 不 不
No! No, no.
絕對不是那種 我喜歡這個稱呼
Definitely not that. I like that.
好吧 好吧
Okay, okay.
嗯 我能問你 我們能指望你下週日再來嗎
Well, can I ask you, can we count on you to join us next Sunday?
是的 嗯 還有這週三
Yeah. Well, and also this Wednesday.
哦 哇 是的 周 週三是什麼活動
Oh. Wow. Yeah. What's-what's Wednesday?
呃 我辦了一個單身人士晚餐
Uh, I run a singles dinner,
這周在紅龍蝦餐廳
and this week's gonna be at a Red Lobster.
我喜歡紅龍蝦
I love a Red Lobster.
我指的不只是海鮮 那些奶酪餅乾
I mean, not just the seafood. Those cheese biscuits...
嗯哼 我是說 是的
Mm-hmm. I mean, yeah.
我 我是說 你會去嗎
I-I mean, are you gonna be there?
嗯 莉
Hmm. Leigh?
你覺得你會來參加我們的第一次單身晚餐嗎
You think you're gonna join us for our first single dinner?
嗯 我從來沒想過自己是單身
Well, I never thought of myself as being a single,
但是 當然 是的 我 我會去的
but, sure, yeah, I-I'll-I'll go.
好的 是的 我 我會去的
Okay. Yeah, I'll-I'll be there.
算上我一個 好的
Count me in.  Okay.
很高興見到你 非常感謝
Good to see you. Thank you so much.
謝謝你今天加入我們 真的很感激
Thank you for joining us today. Really appreciate it.
我更喜歡當約翰
I liked being John
勝過當傑夫
better than I liked being Jeff.
週三見 週三 是的 女士
See you on Wednesday. Wednesday. Yes, ma'am.
約翰是個好人
John was a good guy.
人們喜歡他
People liked him.
莉似乎也喜歡他
Leigh seemed to like him, too.
但像她這樣的女孩不可能真的愛上
But there was no way a girl like her was gonna really fall
一個穿女式跑鞋和蜘蛛俠T恤的男人
for a guy in women's running shoes and a Spider-Man T-shirt.
而且 我真的需要去看牙醫
Also, I really needed to see a dentist.
靠糖果維生對牙齒不好
Living on candy is hard on your teeth.
下午好 你好嗎
Good afternoon. How are you?
很好 先生 你好嗎
Good, sir. How are you?
看看這些你能給我多少錢
See what you give me for these.
呃 每個十塊怎麼樣 三百
Uh, how about ten apiece? 300.
好的 就三百
Yeah, I'll go 300.
好的 成交 是的 先生
Okay, let's do that. Yeah, deal. Yes, sir.
29號需要經理授權
M.O.D. on number 29.
14個蛀牙 對成年人來說很多了
14 cavities. That's a lot of cavities for an adult.
是的 對不起
Yeah, I'm sorry.
我只是有點
I just have a bit...
我想 天生就有點愛吃甜食
naturally, I guess, a bit of a sweet tooth,
而且我最近能接觸到很多很好的糖果
and I've had access to a lot of really good candy.
只是沒能 張大嘴巴
Just haven't been able to... Open your mouth
停 好的
wide, please. ...S-stop. Okay.
看看這些
Look at those.
哦 哇
Oh, wow.
你好
Hello.
女士們好 嗨
Hello, ladies.  Hi!
嗨 嗨
Hi. Hi.
大家都好嗎 很好
How is everyone? Good.
哦 好的
Oh, okay.
我以為這是單身早午餐
I thought this was a singles brunch,
不是超模早午餐
not a supermodel brunch.
哦
Ooh.
你可以擠到我們這邊來坐
You could always squeeze in down here by us.
嗯 我們想歡迎你 約翰
Well, we wanted to welcome you, John.
是的 歡迎 歡迎
Yes. Welcome, welcome.
我是今天唯一會來的男士嗎
Am I the only guy that's gonna be here today?
是的 嗯哼 是的 你是
Yes. Uh-huh. Yep. You are.
結果確實如此 是的 對的 好的
Turns out to be so, yes. Right. Okay.
是的 希望我們沒有讓你不知所措
Yes. I hope we're not overwhelming for you.
哦 不 不 不 我其實 我 我非常喜歡
Oh, no, no, no, I'm actually... I-I'm liking it very much.
好的 很好 我喜歡有這麼多新朋友
Okay, good. I love having so many new friends,
尤其是漂亮的朋友 呃
especially beautiful friends. Um...
哦 嘴真甜
Ooh.  Sweet one.
所以 約翰 我聽說你為政府工作 是哪方面的工作
So, John, I understand you work for the government. What kind of work?
我 我很想透露細節 但我是臥底 所以 呃
I-I would love to get into those details, but I'm undercover, so, um...
哦 聽起來很神秘
Oh, that sounds mysterious.
不 我可以保證沒那麼神秘
No, I can promise it's not that mysterious.
其實挺無聊的
It's really quite boring.
我從不知道夏洛特這裏有個情報部門
I never knew there was an intelligence unit here in Charlotte.
哦 你是執法部門的嗎
Oh, are you law enforcement?
我現在退休了 但以前是
I'm retired now, but I was.
哇 太厲害了
Wow. That's amazing.
我 我 呃
Am I, am I, uh...
我被逮捕了嗎 這是怎麼回事
Am I arrested? How does this work?
我不想讓你不高興
I don't want to make you upset.
你讓大家都尷尬了 莎莉
You're embarrassing everyone, Sally.
他不是來接受審問的
He did not come here to be interrogated.
不 不 不 我其實很喜歡
No, no, no, I actually really like it.
有她在這裏我感覺安全多了
I feel a lot safer with her here.
呃 但是 是的
Um, but-but yeah.
呃 幾乎每個主要城市都有情報部門
Um, there's intelligence just about in every major city.
我們只是不怎麼宣傳 是的
We just don't advertise that much, yeah.
嗯 如果他是臥底 為什麼會在紅龍蝦的單身晚餐上
Well, if he's undercover, why's he at a singles dinner at Red Lobster?
這是個合理的問題
That's a fair question.
嗯
Well...
這是個合理的問題 我 我可以
That's a fair question. I-I can...
那是 那是個非機密問題
That is, that is a question that is not classified.
我在這裏可能是為了尋找下一任約翰·佐林太太
I am here possibly looking for the next Ms. John Zorin.
哦 拜託 哦 拜託
Oh, please. Oh, please.
看 但 但是有個問題
See, but there-there is a problem, though.
我有點困擾 因為這裏漂亮的選擇太多了
I'm having a bit of an issue that there's just too many beautiful choices here
讓我無從選擇
to choose from.
不 我 我很抱歉 我不該那麼說的
No, I'm-I'm sorry. I should not have said that.
我媽媽總是告訴我不要讚美女人的美貌
My mom always told me do not compliment a woman
因為那會讓她不自在
on her beauty because it makes her self-conscious.
呃 總是從她們的鞋子開始誇起
Um, always start with their shoes.
說到鞋子 等一下
Speaking of. Hold on a second.
讓我鑽到桌子底下看看
Let me get under this table.
失禮了
Excuse me.
下面有幾雙高筒靴
Got some high boots down there.
早午餐穿細高跟鞋 可以的 姑娘
Stilettos at brunch. All right, girl.
好吧 好吧
Okay, okay.
這裏開始熱起來了
It is getting hot in here.
不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no.
剛才真的很有趣
That was really fun.
聽著 我不常出門 所以這對我來說很有趣
Look, I don't get out much, so this was fun for me.
我也是
Me neither.
你確實讓她們很開心
You sure made their day.
她們讓我很開心 真的
They made my day, truly.
這是我的車 我是說 我從來沒
This is my car. I mean, I've never been...
這是你的車 哦 斯巴魯 是的
This is you? Ooh, a Subaru. Yeah.
是的
Yeah.
我喜歡
I like it.
好了 我 我在鼓起勇氣
All right, I'm-I'm getting my courage up.
呃
Um...
我有兩個問題要問你
I have two questions to ask you.
兩個 就兩個
Two? Just two?
是的 好吧 說吧
Yeah. All right. Let's hear it.
鼓點 第一個問題 說吧
Drumroll. Give me the first one. Go.
呃 你是同性戀 對吧
Um, you're gay, right?
什麼 我是什麼 你是同性戀
What? I'm what? You're gay.
同性戀 不 是的
Gay? No. Yeah.
什麼
What?
你現在是在開玩笑嗎 不 我
Are you kidding right now? No, I...
不 我是說 聽著 我對同性戀沒有意見
No, I mean, look, I don't have anything against gays.
我喜歡同性戀 但是 像 我 絕對不是
I love gays, but, like, I'm... no, absolutely not.
你只是 你為什麼覺得我是同性戀
You just... What made you think I was gay?
你看起來就像姐妹一樣
You just seem like one of the girls.
或者 好像你很喜歡女鞋
Or, like, you seem to love women's shoes.
不 不是那樣的
No, that's not what that was.
好吧 呃呃
All right. Uh-uh.
好吧 嗯 如果那是個不
All right, well, that... if that's a no,
我們可以直接進入第二個問題
we can go straight to question two.
好的 呃 是的 我猜 說吧
Okay. Uh, yeah. I guess, hit me.
呃
Um...
呃 你願意和我約會嗎
Um, would you like to go out with me?
約會嗎
On a date?
好的
Okay.
哇 你真是個非常直接的人
Wow, you're a very forward person.
我 呃
I, uh...
呃 是的 我願意 我非常 真的 非常
Um, yes, I would, I would very much... really, very much...
願意和你約會
like to go out on a date with you.
我不知道 是的
I don't know, yes.
是的 這就是答案
Yes is the answer to that.
好的 好吧
All right. Okay.
我 呃 下週六早上有空
I'm free, um, next Saturday morning?
完美
Perfect.
我來接你 你住哪裏
I'll pick you up. Where do you live?
我住在一個非常無聊的 呃
I live in a really boring, uh,
政府大樓裏 不向公眾公開
government building that's non-disclosed to the public.
這樣如何
How about this?
呃 我們在自由公園見面
Uh, let's meet at Freedom Park.
週六早上八點
Saturday morning, 8:00 a.m.
聽起來像 呃 嗯 聽起來像個約會
Sounds like a, like a... uh, well, sounds like a date.
是個約會 所以這是個約會
It's a date. So it's a date.
好的 再見 好的 再見
Okay. Bye. Okay. Bye.
好的 好的 抱歉 嘿
All right. All right. Sorry. Hey.
你在發抖 我正要
You were shaking, and I was going...
但是別 有輛車 哦 靠
But don't get... There's a car.  Oh, shit.
好的 好的 是的
Okay. All right. Yep.
好吧 剛才真尷尬 好的
All right, that was awkward. Okay.
再見 拜
See ya. Bye!
好熱
It's hot.
哇
Wow.
你身材真好
You're in really good shape.
謝謝 姑娘
Thanks, girl.
我的前夫 傑弗裏 他 是嗎
My ex, Jeffrey, he... Yeah?
什麼 你說了傑弗裏
What? You said Jeffrey.
是的 那是我前夫的名字 傑弗裏
Yeah. That's my ex's name... Jeffrey.
明白了 對的 是的
Got it, right. Yeah.
他叫傑弗裏
His name was Jeffrey?
是的 他身材
Yeah. He was in... Wow.
糟透了
horrible shape.
就像 我們沒有任何
Like, we had no...
沒有任何 只是很久沒見了
No...? It's just been a long time.
哦 好吧 但我們一點都不像
Oh, okay. But we're nothing alike.
很高興知道 是的 我 我喜歡和人交流
Good to know. Yeah, I-I like people.
他不說話
He didn't talk.
他只是在馬桶上看戰爭歷史小說
He just read war history novels on the toilet.
什麼
What?
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
不 傑弗裏 那太噁心了
N-No, Jeffrey, that is gross.
對吧
Right?
他愛他的書 但輪到陪女兒們的時候
He loves his books, but when it comes to time for the girls
或者輔導作業或駕駛課 他就不見人影
or homework or driving lessons, just doesn't show up.
壓力很大
Stressful.
我只是覺得你的生活需要多一點樂趣
I just think you need a little bit more fun in your life,
說實話
to be honest.
好的
Okay.
你想現在回我那兒找點樂子嗎
Do you want to go back to mine and have some fun right now?
什麼
What?
真的嗎 嗯哼
Really? Mm-hmm.
是的 非常想 是的
Yes. Very much, yes.
我非常 是的 嗯哼
I would very much... yeah, mm-hmm.
好的 嗯哼 是的 現在嗎
Okay. Mm-hmm. Yeah. Now?
是的 好吧
Yeah. All right.
告訴過你我不是同性戀
Told you I wasn't gay.
閉嘴
Shut up.
跟我說說你的女兒們
Tell me about your daughters.
她們叫迪伊和林賽
Their names are Dee and Lindsay.
迪伊11歲
Dee's 11.
她很敏感 有創造力
She's pretty sensitive and creative.
她就像 我不知道
She's like... I don't know.
她 她從嬰兒時期起就不讓我剪她的頭髮
She-she hasn't let me cut her hair since she was a baby.
她就是那種孩子
She's one of those kids.
林賽16歲
And then Lindsay's 16.
她門上有個牌子寫著
She has a sign on her door that says,
情感不可用
"Emotionally unavailable."
她剛拿到學習駕照
She also just got her learner's permit
但拒絕開車 即使她想要自由
but refuses to drive, even though she wants her freedom,
所以我們就這樣僵持著 哦 是嗎
so that's where we're at. Oh, is that right?
嗯 我開車技術很好
Well, I'm a good driver.
如果你想讓我教她 我 我很樂意
If you want me to teach her, I-I'll happily do it.
我們才剛認識
We just met.
說得好 那是
That's a good point. That's a...
是的 我知道
Yeah, I know.
呃 我只是喜歡孩子 所以
Um, I just love kids, so...
好吧 嗯 也許 也許你哪天可以見見她們
Okay, well, maybe... maybe you could meet 'em sometime.
你知道 就像 也許你可以過來
You know, like, maybe you could come over for...
某個週末吃披薩 也許
for pizza one weekend, maybe?
像個披薩派對 我們能開個披薩派對嗎
Like a pizza party? Can we have a pizza party?
像個披薩星期六
Like a pizza Saturday?
我已經很久沒出門了
I haven't been out of the house,
更別說約會了 好嗎 好的
let alone on a date, okay? Okay.
很久了 嗯哼
In a very long time. Mm-hmm.
呃 我 我不知道我的女兒們是否準備好了 你知道
Um, I... I don't know if my girls are ready for, you know,
媽 媽媽現在就開始約會
M-Mom to be dating just yet.
我理解
I get that.
我們仍然可以開個披薩派對 就讓它
We can still have a pizza party and just make it
完全正常
just totally normal.
我只是個來自教堂的朋友 你知道
I'm just a friend from church, you know,
碰巧是個政府間諜
that happens to be a government spy.
非同性戀的那種
A non-gay one.
你知道 一個非同性戀的政府間諜
You know, a non-gay government spy
只是過來 你知道
that just comes over and wants to, you know,
和你還有你的女兒們一起吃披薩
have pizza with you and your daughters.
你知道 就讓它變得正常 好的
You know, just make it normal. Okay.
你 你不正常 約翰
You're-you're not normal, John,
但是
but...
我喜歡你
I like you.
你知道什麼不正常嗎 嗯
You know what's not normal? Hmm?
你一直都看起來這麼誘人嗎
You just look like this all the time?
看起來很吸引人
Looking inviting.
哦
Oh.
他來了 好嗎
He's here. Okay?
你好
Hello.
請進
Please come in.
哇 好多食物啊
Wow, that's a lot of food.
姑娘們 這是我的朋友約翰
Girls, this is my friend John.
約翰 這些是我的女兒們
John, these are my girls.
嘿 姑娘們
Hey, girls.
呃 嗨 我是 我是約翰·佐林
Uh, hi. I'm-I'm John Zorin.
我是你們媽媽在教堂的好朋友
I'm your mom's good friend from church.
你一定是迪伊了
You must be Dee.
是迪莉婭的簡稱嗎
That's short for Delia?
是的 是的
Yeah. Yes.
你一定是林賽了 那是
You must be Lindsay, and that's short for...
那不是什麼簡稱
That's not short for anything at all, actually.
聽著 我聽說過很多關於你們的事
Look, I've heard so much about you guys.
呃 我聽說的一件事
Uh, and one of the things that I have heard,
就是你 迪伊 和我一樣是塞爾達傳說的超級粉絲
is that you, Dee, happen to be a huge fan of Zelda, like I am.
是真的嗎
Is that true?
是的 是嗎
Yeah. Is that right?
很好 因為我給你帶來了這個林克玩偶
Good, 'cause I got you this Link doll.
還有一個問題
And another question:
你玩過四支劍嗎
Have you played Four Swords?
沒有 它太棒了
No. It is so amazing,
它附帶這個特殊控制器
and it comes with this special controller
我待會兒教你用
that I'll teach you how to use later
直到你能打敗我
until you can whup my butt,
你可能很快就能做到
which you'll probably be able to do really quickly
因為我聽說你是個塞爾達大師
"cause I hear you're, like, a Zelda master."
謝謝 是的 塞爾達起作用了
Thanks. Yes. Zelda worked.
搞定一個
One down.
林賽 給你的
Lindsay, for you,
我準備了一些非常憂鬱的青少年音樂
I have an assortment of very angsty teenage music
供你欣賞
for your listening pleasure.
謝謝
Thank you?
不 謝謝你
No, thank you.
很高興認識你 約翰·佐林
Nice to meet you, John Zorin,
媽媽在教堂的朋友
Mom's friend from church.
你要去哪兒 我有作業要做
Where are you going? I have homework.
沒關係
It's okay.
也許下次吧
Maybe next time.
好嗎
Okay?
好嗎 別擔心
All right? Don't worry.
我 呃 也正好給你帶了點東西
I, uh, also happened to have gotten you something,
莉小姐 哦
Miss Leigh. Oh.
這一切都太貼心了
This is all so sweet.
我為林賽感到抱歉
I'm sorry about Lindsay.
我 我覺得這對她來說可能很難接受
I-I thought this might be hard for her.
是的 不 聽著 我理解
Yeah. No, and, look, I understand that.
這個必須放在頂上
This one has to go on top.
是的 最頂上部分
Yeah, the top, top part.
這個必須放在
And this one has to go...
但是等等 燈在哪裏
But wait, where's the light...
等等 你得連接上
Wait, you got to connect.
哦 卡噠聲
Oh, the click.
我喜歡這卡噠聲
I love the click.
這個必須放在那個上面 迪伊
And this one has to go on that.  Dee?
是的
Yeah.
11點了 超過11點了
It's 11:00. Past 11:00.
哦 拜託 讓我們把這個做完 求你了
Oh, come on, let us finish this. Please?
求你了 她是最棒的搭建者
Please? She's, like, the best builder.
我們離完成只差20個零件了
We're like 20 pieces away from the end.
是的 求你了 媽媽
Yeah, please, Mom.
就差一點了 下次吧 好嗎
So close. Another time, okay?
好吧
Okay.
我和你在一起很開心
I had the best time with you.
好嗎 是的
Okay? Yeah.
我能再見到你嗎
Can I see you again?
我很樂意
I'd like that.
是嗎 是的
Yeah? Yeah.
所以 如果晚了 我就來敲你的窗戶
So, if it's late, I'll just come and, like, tap on your window?
哦
Oh.
我不知道我是不是
I don't know if I'm a...
敲窗戶的那種女孩 約翰
"tap on the window" kind of girl, John.
不是嗎
No?
好吧 那我敲前門怎麼樣
All right, how about I just knock on the front door?
好的
Okay.
我會回家
I'll be home
當你的夜晚陷入困境
When your nights are troubled
當你孤單一人
And you're all alone
哦 當你情緒低落
Ooh When you're feeling down
哦 你需要一些同情
Ooh You need some sympathy
哦
Ooh
身邊空無一人
There's no one else around
哦 陪伴你
Ooh To keep you company
哦
Ooh
啊 記住 寶貝
Ah Remember, baby
你永遠可以
You can always
依靠我 依靠我
Count on me Count on me
我會回家
I'll be home
我會回家 我會回家
I'll be home I'll be home
我會回家
I'll be home
無論你漂泊何方
Wherever you may wander
無論你漫遊何處
Wherever you may roam
哦 你回來吧
Ooh You come back
我會在這裏等你
I'll be waiting here for you
哦
Ooh
啊 我會在這裏
Ah I'll be here
安慰你
To comfort you
陪你度過難關 陪你度過難關
And see you through And see you through
我會回家 我會回家
I'll be home I'll be home
萬聖節再見
Goodbye, Halloween.
我會回家
I'll be home
火雞時間到了
Turkey time.
別碰那個燈 我不會的
Don't hit the light.  I won't.
是的 也許明年我們應該買個奧蒂斯的充氣玩偶
Yeah, maybe next year we should get an inflatable Otis.
嘿 我 我這次不插手了
Hey. I-I'm not stepping in this time.
好嗎 你得自己處理 你得自己處理
Okay? You got to do it. You got to do it.
你得給那個惡霸鼻子一拳 懂嗎
You got to punch the bully in the nose, you know?
我的夥計 奧蒂斯 是的
My man, Otis. Yeah.
是的 我有事要告訴你 米奇
Yeah. I need to tell you something, Mitch.
哇 好的 是的
Whoa, okay. Yeah.
我是說 好的 什麼
I mean... okay. What?
呃
Um...
什麼
What?
呃
Uh...
請說吧
Please say it.
不 對不起 呃 我只是 什麼 什麼
No, I'm sorry. Um, I'm just... What, what?
呃 我 我 呃 說吧
Uh, I was, I was, um... Say it.
奧蒂斯 拜託 我
Otis, come on. I...
說吧
Just say it.
我想告訴你 我 我 什麼
I wanted to tell you I-I... What?
我按你說的打掃了儲藏室
I sweeped up the stockroom like you said.
好的 就這個 是的
Okay, is that it? Yeah.
不 不
No. No.
我媽媽過去常告訴我 要小心你觸摸的東西
My mom used to tell me be careful what you touch.
她說移動一粒沙子就會改變
She said that moving one grain of sand changes everything
整個宇宙中的一切
in the whole universe.
我想人們稱之為蝴蝶效應
I think people call it the butterfly effect.
就是一隻蝴蝶扇動翅膀就能
That just one butterfly flapping its wings can
在世界另一端引發颶風
make a hurricane on the other side of the world.
在我們意識到之前 我們就撞上了彼此的路徑
And before we know it, we're banging into each other's paths
並改變了發生的事情
and changing what happens.
你確定想要劉海嗎
Are you sure you want bangs?
確定
Sure.
這是個很大的改變
It's a big change.
關於劉海的問題是
Thing is about bangs,
大約只有千分之一的人
there's only about one in a thousand people
留劉海真的好看
that actually look good with bangs,
但好消息是我認為你可能是其中之一
but good news is I think that you might be one of them.
哦 天啊
Oh, God.
沒人注意到蝴蝶扇動翅膀
No one notices the butterfly flapping its wings
直到所有人都感受到風暴
until everyone feels the storm.
我知道風暴即將來臨
I knew a storm was coming.
我知道如果我在一個地方待太久
I knew if I stayed in one place too long,
最終會有人認出我
eventually someone would recognize me.
我知道我必須離開
I knew I had to leave.
我只是不想一個人走
I just didn't want to go alone.
你覺得你有可能搬到別的地方去嗎
You think you could ever just move somewhere else?
比如海邊什麼的 在一個新地方重新開始
Like a beach or something? Start over in a new place?
我不知道 約翰
I don't know, John.
我 我需要回到這裏 你知道
I-I need to come back here, you know?
我們可以帶上姑娘們
We could take the girls.
收拾行李就走
Just pack up and go.
嗯 那是
Mm. That's...
不 我做不到
No, I can't do that.
我做不到
I can't do that.
我的生活在這裏 約翰
My life is here, John.
你正在放手
You're letting go
如果這是真的
And if it's real
嗯 我不想知道
Well, I don't want to know
別說
Don't speak...
停止解釋
Stop explaining
別告訴我 因為那會傷害
Don't tell me 'Cause it hurts
別說
Don't speak
我知道你在
I know what you're...
我不需要你的理由
I don't need your reasons
別告訴我 因為那會傷害
Don't tell me 'Cause it hurts
我們的記憶
Our memories
它們可以很誘人
They can be inviting
但有些在情慾上很誘人
But some Erotically enticing
書寫著
Writing
當我們死去
As we die
你和我都
Both you and I...
停止解釋
Stop explaining
別告訴我 因為那會傷害
Don't tell me 'Cause it hurts
不 不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no
搞什麼鬼
What the fuck?
什麼 哦 我的天啊
What? Oh, my God!
哦 我的天啊
Oh, my God!
哦 我的天啊 你塊頭真大
Oh, my God, there's a lot of you.
他 他很大只 他光著身子
He's-he's big. He's naked!
他朝我衝過來
He came at me.
先生 他還在這裏嗎
Sir, is he still here?
我不知道
I don't know.
我聽到 外面的 警報門響了
I heard the-the outer... the alarm door went off.
所以他可能出去了
So he may have gone outside?
呃 是的 夏洛特警察
Uh, yes. Charlotte Police!
夏洛特警察 夏洛特警察
Charlotte Police! Charlotte Police!
警察局 警察局
Police department! Police department!
警察局
Police department!
警察局 警察局
Police department! Police department!
警報在響
The alarm was going off.
我們回到這裏時 門是虛掩的
When we came back here, the door was ajar,
所以我們真的認為他是從這條路出去的
so we really believe he went out this way.
我們可以看整個過程的錄像 警官
We could watch the whole thing, Officer,
因為我知道怎麼 按播放鍵 所以
'cause I know how to... press "play" on this thing, so...
米奇 是的
Mitch? Yeah?
好消息是你們店裏到處都有監控攝像頭
The good news is you have surveillance cameras
是的 是的
all over the store. Yes. Yes.
壞消息
Bad news...
是它們都沒在錄像
is none of them were recording.
你需要修好它們
You need to fix that.
現在 除了那個裸體男人 你們有沒有注意到
Now, besides the naked guy, have you noticed
這裏有什麼奇怪的事情發生
anything strange happening around here?
呃 呃
Uh, uh...
呃 嗯 我們丟了很多遊戲庫存
Uh, well, we're-we're missing a lot of gaming inventory.
很多是多少
What's a lot?
相當多
A substantial amount.
你得弄點真正的安保來 米奇
You're gonna have to get some real security in here, Mitch.
這家玩具反斗城的員工們
Workers at this Toys "R" Us
正在為假日搶購做準備
are prepping for the holiday rush,
但店經理米奇·哈金說
but store manager Mitch Haggin says
他沒想到今天早上會看到這樣的景象
he did not expect to see what he saw this morning:
一個強壯 非常高大的裸體男人
a strong, very tall, naked man.
呃 一個 一個裸體男人朝我衝過來
Uh, a-a naked guy ran at me.
我覺得他要殺我 我就跑開了
I think he was gonna kill me, and I ran away,
把自己鎖在辦公室裏
locked myself in my office.
當我問那個裸體男人是否會
When I asked if the naked man
嚇跑假日購物者時
would scare off holiday shoppers,
哈金先生說他正在僱傭全天候保安
Mr. Haggin said he was hiring round-the-clock security.
我們現在有一個非常好的安保系統 肯定的
We have a really good security system here now, for sure.
家庭可以感到安全
Families can feel safe.
這是一個來過聖誕的安全地方
This is a safe place to come for Christmas.
我覺得看起來很棒
I think it looks great.
嗨 嗨
Hi. Hi.
嗨
Hi.
我們差不多準備好了
We're almost ready to go.
主啊 我們感謝你
Lord, we want to thank you
賜予這美好的食物
for this wonderful food,
我們感謝你賜予家庭的禮物 阿們
and we want to thank you for the gift of family. Amen.
阿們
Amen.
感恩節快樂 感恩節快樂
Happy Thanksgiving. Happy Thanksgiving.
感恩節快樂
Happy Thanksgiving.
所以 莉 什麼事
So, Leigh. Yes?
你為什麼不跟我們大家講講那個裸體男人的故事
Why don't you tell us all that story about the naked man.
哦 那 那沒什麼 大家
Oh, it-it's nothing, y'all.
外面很冷
It... it was cold outside,
一個無家可歸的人需要洗個澡
and a homeless man needed to take a shower.
是的 但如果他也是個殺手呢
Yeah, but what if he's also a killer?
他 別太誇張了
He's... Stop being overdramatic.
他不是殺手
He's not a killer.
你媽媽完全正確
Your mom's totally right.
他絕對不是殺手
He's definitely not a killer.
你不知道 約翰
You don't know that, John.
嗯 如果他是殺手 他早就殺了他了 對吧
Well, if he was a killer, he'd have killed him, right?
呃 今天的報紙說有價值一萬美元的遊戲被盜了
Uh, the paper said today that there was $10,000 in video games stolen.
嗯
Mm.
我不知道這是不是巧合
I don't know if that's a coincidence or not.
那是一大筆錢
That is a lot of money.
嗯 我不知道 媽媽
Well, I don't know, Mom.
也許你應該辭職
Maybe you should quit.
你有碩士學位
You have a master's degree,
我認為不值得冒這個風險
and I don't think it's worth the risk.
那裏似乎很可怕
It seems scary over there.
我是說 那不是最壞的主意 我猜
I mean, that's not the worst idea, I guess.
我喜歡我的工作 等等 打住
I like my job. Wait. Hold up.
剛才你還讓人覺得那裏不危險
Earlier, you just made it seem like it wasn't dangerous.
所以 如果不危險 那她為什麼突然要辭職
So, if it's not dangerous, then-then why does she have to quit so suddenly?
是的 我不知道 對不起
Yeah. I don't know. I'm sorry.
呃 我 我說了她必須辭職嗎
Uh, did I, did I say she had to quit?
我覺得我沒有 實際上
I don't think I did, actually.
我想我只是同意下面林賽的看法
I think I was just agreeing with Lindsay down here.
我剛才只是說林賽
I was just saying here that Lindsay
其實有個好主意
actually has a great idea.
如果她想辭職
If she wants to quit,
她就會有更多時間陪她的女兒們
then she would have more time with her girls.
是的 現在 大家
Yeah. Now, everybody,
別太嚴肅了 因為 呃
let's not get too serious, because, uh...
我只是覺得有點好笑
I just think it's kind of funny.
我想像那個人 他正要去上班
I imagine the guy, he's just going to work,
只是平常的一天 然後他看到個裸體男人
just a normal day, and then he sees a naked guy
在他的玩具店裏亂跑
running around inside his toy store.
這讓我都想去那裏工作了 真的
Makes me want to get a job there, actually.
哦 卡米 保佑你
Oh, Kami, bless you.
是的 我只是覺得真的很好笑 就這樣
Yeah, I just think it's really funny, that's all.
我不覺得好笑 羅恩
I don't think it's funny, Ron.
我 我覺得很可悲
I-I think it's sad.
我是說 有人如此絕望
I mean, someone's so desperate
不得不在玩具店的水槽裏洗澡
they had to bathe in a toy store sink,
而我們卻在這裏邊吃邊笑
while we eat and laugh about it?
我是說 也許我們不是好撒瑪利亞人
I mean, maybe we aren't Good Samaritans.
嗯
Mm.
也許你做的不是最好的決定
Maybe you aren't making the best decisions.
不好意思 女士
Excuse me, ma'am?
選擇在那裏工作 而我和迪伊獨自在家
Choosing to work there while Dee and I are home alone,
等著有人來接我們送我們去別的地方
waiting for someone to pick us up to take us places?
就像 我們 哇 哇
Like, we... Whoa, whoa.
老實說 你已經夠大可以自己開車了
If we're being honest, you're old enough to drive yourself.
我沒有駕照
I don't have a license.
我告訴過你我會教你 好嗎
I told you I would teach you. Okay?
我甚至不能和你一起坐在車裏
I can't even sit in the car with you.
現在爸爸不在這裏 你帶回來這個怪人
And now that Dad's not here, you bring around this weirdo,
我們就該接受嗎
and we're supposed to just accept it?
我 我希望那點性值得你這麼做
I-I hope the sex is worth it.
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey.
林
Lin...
對不起
Sorry.
我們的教堂 是的
Our church.  Yeah.
哇
Wow.
喂 呃 嗨
Hello? Uh, hi.
呃 我是表弟奧利弗
Um, this is Cousin Oliver.
我打電話找史蒂夫
I was just calling for Steve.
現在是早上七點
It's 7:00 in the morning.
呃 今天也是12月1號
Uh, it's also December 1st,
我們幾個月前有過約定
and we had a conversation a few months back
我應該在今天12月1號打回來
that I should call back on December 1st.
是的 你打回來了 他在睡覺
Yeah, you just call back. He's sleeping.
好吧 你能叫醒他嗎
Okay, well, can you just wake him up for me?
呃 就告訴他是表弟奧利弗
Um, just tell him it's Cousin Oliver.
好嗎 很緊急
All right? It's urgent.
寶貝 嗯 嗯
Baby. Mm. Mm.
是你表弟 是表弟奧利弗
It's your cousin. It's Cousin Oliver.
告訴他我在睡覺
Tell him I'm asleep.
媽了個逼 真他媽該死
Motherfucker. Goddamn.
他說 我們週日再辦
He says... We can do it Sunday.
他在睡覺 而且
he's asleep and that
你應該下週日來見他
you should come see him next Sunday.
下週日 好的 太好了 他還在費耶特維爾嗎
Next Sunday. Okay, great. Is he still in Fayetteville?
不 不 是雙松汽車旅館
No. No. It's the Twin Pines Motel.
雙松 好的
Twin Pines. Okay.
204房間
Room 204.
204 我記住了 別當個
204. I got it. And don't be
他媽的白癡去坐公交車
a fucking dumbass and take the bus.
他說別當個他媽的白癡去坐公交車
He says don't be a fucking dumbass and take the bus.
他想知道你有沒有車
He wants to know if you got a car.
有的 告訴中士 呃 我會搞定車的事
Yep. Tell the sarge, uh, I'll take care of that
我會按計劃在週日見他
and I'll see him on Sunday as scheduled.
嗨 早上好
H-Hi. Morning.
你沒告訴我你要出趟門
You didn't tell me you had to take a trip.
你不該聽到那個的
You weren't supposed to hear that.
好的
Okay.
聽著 沒什麼大不了的
Look, it's not a big deal.
我只是需要去報到一下
I just have to go and just check in.
就這樣 好的
That's all. Okay.
啵
Mwah.
早上好 林賽
Morning, Lindsay.
早上好 莉 早上好 迪伊
Good morning, Leigh. Good morning, Dee.
大家都想說早上好嗎
Everybody want to say "good morning"?
早上好 約翰
Morning, John.
好了 誰想先道歉 嗯
All right, who wants to apologize first, hmm?
不 你嗎
No? You?
拜託 孩子們
Come on, guys.
沒人有話要對彼此說嗎
Nobody has anything to say to each other?
聽著 家人之間會吵架
Look, families fight.
這沒關係 但他們也會和好
That's fine, but they also make up.
來吧
Come on.
我為我的行為方式道歉 林賽
I'm sorry for the way I've been acting, Lindsay.
做得好
Great work.
我不該在迪伊面前說關於性的事
I shouldn't have said the thing about sex in front of Dee.
嗯 是的
Mm. Yeah.
還有
And...
還有 你說到點子上了
And? You got it.
還有 我需要搭車去道格家
And I need a ride to Doug's.
不 那不是
Nope. That wasn't...
你哪兒也去不了
You aren't getting a ride anywhere.
你知道你昨晚讓我多難堪嗎
Do you have any idea how much you embarrassed me last night?
我讓你難堪
I embarrassed you?
約翰 你能開車送我嗎
John, will you drive me?
你不能虐待他然後又向他求助
You do not get to abuse him and then ask him for favors.
沒關係 我 我不介意送她
It's okay. I-I don't mind driving her.
不 別摻和 約翰 看 他不介意
No, stay out of this, John. See, he doesn't mind.
如果她想去哪兒 她可以學開車
If she wants to go somewhere, she can learn to drive.
我永遠不會再坐那輛手動擋的車跟你學車了
I'm not driving in that car with that stick shift with you ever.
那你以後就再也別想去任何地方了
Well, then I guess you'll never go anywhere again!
好了 暫停 暫停 永遠
Okay, time-out. Time-out. Ever!
對不起 我能讓我媽媽開車送我去地方嗎
I'm sorry, can I ask my mom to drive me places
因為她是我母親 好了 停下
'cause she's my mother? Okay, stop.
我有個主意 好嗎
I have an idea, okay?
我有個主意 聽我說 是個好主意
I have an idea. Hear me out. It's a great idea.
我們需要一輛破車
We need a beater.
破車到底是什麼 約翰
What even is a beater, John?
他們告訴我 來吧
Come, they told me
啪 隆 啪 啪 啪
Pa, rum, pum, pum, pum...
那輛車不錯啊 是吧
That's a nice ride right there, huh?
經典的1999年款 里程數很低
Classic 1999 with very low mileage.
是嗎 顏色也很好
Yeah? Great color, too.
很棒的家庭用車
Awesome family car.
是自動擋
It's automatic.
是自動擋 價格很好
It is automatic. Great price.
你們想試試嗎 是的
You guys want to try it out? Yeah.
鑰匙就在這裏 看
Got the keys right here. Look at that.
座椅很舒服 對吧
It's nice seats, right?
你知道 現代的車沒有這種感覺了
You know, modern cars just don't have the same feel.
這有點像黃金時代
This is kind of like the golden era.
90年代
The '90s.
你知道 就是 他們不再生產這樣的現代車了 你知道
You know, just...  They don't make modern cars like this anymore, you know?
是的 這些就像沙發一樣
Yeah. These-these are like sofas.
大家繫好安全帶了嗎 是的 是的
You guys buckled up? Yeah, yeah.
這裏有警察嗎 哦 不 不
Any cops around here ever? Oh, no, no.
這裏沒人會攔你
Nobody's gonna stop you here.
稍微開快一點
Just gonna push it just a little bit.
好的
Okay.
哦 哦 哦 哦
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
馬力不小 好的
It's got some horsepower. Okay.
好了 好了
All right, all right.
不錯的V6發動機
Got a nice V-6...
好的 好的
Okay. Okay.
嘿 嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
嘿 先生 先生
Hey, sir! Sir!
小心 來了
Watch out! Here we go.
哦 哦 哦
Oh. Oh! Oh!
操
Fuck!
操 減速 減速
Fuck! Slow down! Slow down!
減速 減速 這是輛二手車
Slow down! Slow down! It's a used car!
減速
Slow down!
減速 減速
Slow down! Slow down!
我為他盡了全力
I played my best for him
啪 隆 啪 啪 啪
Pa, rum, pum, pum, pum...
你們沒事吧
You guys okay?
媽了個逼 是嗎
Motherfucker! Yeah?
好的 很好
All right, good.
你怎麼回事 老兄
What's wrong with you, man?
冷靜點 不 不 下車
Calm down. No, no, get out.
冷靜點 不 不 不 下車 下車
Calm down. No, no, no. Get out. Get out!
我開回去 林賽 林賽 停下
I'm driving us back. Lindsay, Lindsay. Stop.
冷靜點 林賽 到前面來 你開車 你到後面去
Calm down. Lindsay, get up here. You drive. You in the back.
不 也許她不該開車 約翰
No, maybe she shouldn't drive, John.
不 不 她是個孩子 她不能開車
No. No, she's a kid! She can't drive!
這裏車多 車多 不 她能開 聽著
It's busy here. It's busy. No, she can drive. Listen.
不 現在把鑰匙給我 不 不
No, give me the keys right now. No, no.
停下 停下 冷靜點 好嗎
Stop, stop. Calm down, okay?
你怎麼教孩子游泳 你把他們扔進水裏
How do you teach a kid to swim? You throw them in the water.
對吧 如果你想讓她開車
Right? If you want her to drive,
我們就得讓她開 哦 是的 上 林賽
we got to let her drive. Oh, yeah. Go, Lindsay.
她甚至有駕照嗎
Does she even have a license?
她有學習駕照 沒有
She has her permit.  No.
不 你不能用學習駕照試駕
No, you cannot test-drive with a permit.
聽著 聽著 我要買這輛車
Look, listen, I'm gonna purchase this car
如果這位年輕女士批准 我會付現金
if the young lady approves, and I'm gonna pay cash.
你覺得怎麼樣
How's that sound to you?
我讓你拿著
I'll let you hold it.
來吧
Come on.
是的
Yes.
到前面來 你開車
Get up here. You're driving.
好的
All right.
安全帶 安全第一
Seat belts. Safety first.
好的 這不是手動擋
All right, this is not a manual transmission.
這是自動擋 所以容易多了
This is an automatic, so it's so much easier.
你可以完全忘記你的左腳
You can just forget about your left foot.
全靠右腳
It's all right foot.
所以把你的右腳放在剎車上
So put your right foot on that brake right there,
那個大踏板
the big pedal.
是的 踩到底 踩到底 用力踩實
Yep, push it all the way in. All the way in. Real firm.
好的 現在用你的右手
Okay, now you're gonna take your right hand,
把它拉向你 然後向下推到 D 檔
you're gonna pull that towards you and down to "D."
完美 現在鬆開
Perfect. Now let it go.
回到二點
Back at two.
好的 我們不用擔心油門
All right. We're not gonna worry about the gas.
你只要把腳從剎車上慢慢鬆開
You're just gonna ease your foot off the brake
我們就會向前移動 就這樣
and we're just gonna move forward, and that's it.
好嗎 深呼吸
All right? Take a big breath.
你能行的
You got this.
你能行的 來吧
You got it. Come on.
你能行的 走 走 走 走 走
You got it. Go, go, go, go, go.
是的 是的 是的 是的 很好
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. That's good.
不錯 很好
Nice. Good one.
好了 一家人
All right, family.
我總是喜歡給我滿意的顧客拍照
I always love to take pictures of my happy customers,
如果你們不介意的話
if you guys don't mind.
好的
All right.
笑一個
Big smile.
再來一張 再來一張
One more, one more.
現在 假裝你爸爸差點把車撞了
Now, let's pretend your dad almost crashed the car.
好的
All right.
嘿 很好 很棒 夥計們
Hey, great, great stuff, guys.
非常感謝
Thank you very much.
你開車比他好
You're a better driver than him.
那倒是真的 我覺得和你在一起真的很安全 所以幹得好
That's true, actually. I felt really, really safe with you, so good job.
哦 我很高興
Oh, I'm glad.
謝謝你 約翰 恭喜 老兄
Thank you, John. Congrats, man.
你們姑娘們能在車裏等一下嗎 我和約翰說幾句話
Will you girls wait in the car while I talk to John
就 就一分鐘 給
for just, like, a minute? Here.
好的
Okay.
我們搞到一輛破車了
We got a beater.
是的 我們搞到一輛破車了 是的
Yeah, we got a beater. Yeah.
我必須說出來
I have to say it.
我不喜歡那樣開車 好的
I did not like that driving. Okay.
對不起 我知道
I'm sorry. I know.
我不該那樣做
I shouldn't have done that.
是的
Yeah.
但林賽是個非常 非常好的新手司機
But Lindsay was a really, really good first-time driver.
不是嗎 她開得很好
Wasn't she? She was great.
是的 她做得很好
Yeah. She did so good.
而且 我不知道
And-and... I don't know...
我覺得她開始喜歡我了
I think she's starting to like me.
她們倆都喜歡你呢
They both like you.
她們真的喜歡你 好嗎
They really like you, okay?
我喜歡你
I like you.
只是 只是需要放慢一點節奏 好嗎
Just... just need to slow it down a little bit, okay?
好的
Okay.
我們不需要那麼多東西 約翰
And we don't need so many things, John.
我們只想要你
We just want you.
做你自己就好 正常點
Just be you. Be normal.
我保證 最正常了 好的
I promise. The most normal. Okay.
你去你的旅行 等你回來
You take your trip, and when you come back,
我們會有 有幾個正常的夜晚 好嗎
we'll have a-a few normal nights, okay?
不再有特技駕駛 我保證
No more stunt driving, I promise.
好的
Okay.
哦 天啊
Oh, gosh.
我愛約翰 哦 我的天啊
I love John. Oh, my God.
這輛車 我愛這輛車
The car. I love the car.
這是完美的車 家裏見
It's the perfect car. See you back at the house.
好的
Okay.
嗨 嗨
Hi. Hi.
呃 表弟奧利弗
Uh, Cousin Oliver.
來找史蒂夫 哦 嗯 有點早
Here for Steve. Oh. Mm, it's a little early.
嘿 史蒂夫 什麼事
Hey, Steve?  Yeah?
表弟奧利弗來了
Cousin Oliver's here.
你好啊 傻狗
Hello, dumb dog.
是的 我知道如果我不給你具體時間
Yeah, I knew you'd show up at the crack of dawn
你會在黎明時分出現
if I ain't give you a time.
歡迎回家 中士 老兄
Welcome home, Sarge. Man.
好了 你 哦 老兄
All right, you... Oh, man.
是的 夠了 是的
Yeah, that is enough. Yeah.
媽的 你看起真乾淨 不像個在逃犯
Damn, you look clean for a motherfucker that's on the run.
我在努力 我在努力
I'm trying. I'm trying.
你之前在哪兒躲著 教堂嗎
Where you was hiding out at, church?
你知道我不能告訴你
You know I can't tell you that.
說真的 你之前在哪兒躲著
Seriously, where you hiding out at?
不 我不能告訴你 你不想知道
No, I can't tell you that. You don't want to know that.
你沒跟任何人聯繫 對吧
You ain't got no contact, right?
你沒跟任何人說話 不 不
You ain't talking to nobody? No, no.
好的 因為你知道如果你聯繫了 我就不能幫你了
Okay, 'cause you know if you are, I can't help you.
不 我為什麼要那麼做
No, why would I do that?
你沒事吧 我沒事 我沒事
You good? I'm good. I'm good.
那就看著我
Keep your eyes on me, then.
你為什麼老是東張西望
Why you keep darting them around?
我沒有東張西望 我正看著你呢
I'm not darting them. I'm looking right at you.
你確定你沒事嗎 看
You sure you're all right? Look.
好的
Okay.
我們得
We gonna need to change that hair
拍照前改一下髮型
before we take the photo.
呃 寶貝 你覺得呢 假髮 染髮
Uh, baby, what you think? Wig? Dye?
給他 給他的頭髮
For-for his hair.
我覺得用假髮
I think we do a wig.
是的 別擔心 傑夫 你還是你
Yeah. Don't worry, Jeff. You'll still be you.
但更帥點 像布拉德·皮特
But cuter. Like Brad Pitt.
丑版的布拉德·皮特
Ugly-ass Brad Pitt.
哦 我的天啊
Oh, my God.
寶貝 你是認真的嗎
Baby, are you serious about this?
我 我
I'm-I'm...
這是個撩妹神器
This is a panty dropper.
哦 我的天啊 寶貝 拜託
Oh, my God. Baby, come on.
好的
Okay.
哦
Oh.
你他媽在開玩笑吧 寶貝
You got to be fucking kidding me, baby.
打個招呼 寶貝
Say hi, baby.
哇
Wow.
寶貝 那 那是個好髮型
Baby, th-that's... that's a good one.
很好 對吧 是的
That's good, right? Yeah.
這個你覺得舒服嗎 嗯哼
This one feel good to you? Mm-hmm.
嗯哼 感覺你可以
Mm-hmm? Feels like you could be
以這個身份生活一段時間 嗯哼
this person for a while? Mm-hmm.
準備好了嗎 嗯哼
You ready? Mm-hmm.
等等 等等 等等 等等 別他媽笑了
Wait, wait, wait, wait. Stop with the damn smiling.
你他媽在幹什麼
Fuck you doing?
就 正常表情 不 是的 嚴肅點
Just... normal face. No, yeah, serious.
就像 這是你的護照 你知道
It's like a... it's your passport, you know.
不允許笑
You're not allowed to smile.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
讀讀這玩意兒 好好研究
Read this shit. Study it.
全部
All of it.
好嗎 這將是新的你
All right? It's gonna be the new you.
你是肯尼斯·歐文·格裏芬
You're Kenneth Owen Griffin.
出生於1974年7月7日 來自北卡羅來納州蘭伯頓
Born July 7, 1974, from Lumberton, North Carolina.
現在 我去拿你所有的文件
Now, I'm-a get all your documents.
別擔心任何事
Don't worry about shit.
轉賬 記錄 我會全部搞定 從A到Z
Transfers, records... I'll have it all done, A to Z.
好的 你在想什麼 五千
Okay. What-what are you thinking, like 5K?
哦 不 會比那多得多 老兄
Oh, no, it's gonna be a lot more than that, man.
比那還多 多 多少
More than that? How-how much more?
你以為我不知道你在幹什麼 是吧
You think I don't know what you doing, huh?
你可能有女朋友了 是吧
You probably got a girlfriend, don't you?
什麼 不
What? No.
是的 你有 是的 你有
Yeah, you do. Yeah, you do.
是的 你他媽不擅長這個
Yeah, you not good at this shit.
不擅長什麼 當罪犯 黑鬼
Good at what shit? Being a criminal, nigga.
讓我告訴你
Let me tell you something.
好的罪犯是冷酷的 精於算計的
Good criminals are cold, calculating.
你明白嗎
You understand?
現在 算計這方面你做到了
Now, you got the calculation down,
但是 老兄 你只是 滑稽
but, man, you just... goofy.
價格 要五萬
The price... it's gonna be 50K.
好嗎
All right?
五十 五十 是的
50? 50? Yeah.
嘿 你風險很大 老兄 你能做到嗎
Hey, you a lot of risk, man. Can you do it?
好的 是的
Okay. Yeah.
你打算怎麼做
How you gonna do it?
我會搞到的 我會搞到的
I'll get it. I'll get it.
嗯 如果你在想用槍 幫我個忙
Well, if you're thinking about using a gun, do me a favor.
他媽的要遠離電視
Stay the fuck off the TV.
屋頂人 你明白我在說什麼嗎
Roofman, you understand what I'm saying?
別做任何傻事
Don't do anything stupid.
嗷
Ow.
好的
Okay.
靠
Shit.
搞什麼
What the...?
靠
Shit!
愚蠢的白癡
Stupid idiot!
我們全年90%的銷售額發生在接下來的兩周
90% of our annual sales happens in the next two weeks.
想想看
Think about that.
將會有很多錢進來
There's gonna be a lot of money coming in,
我們需要做好準備
and we need to be ready for it.
考慮到我們最近的挫折
Considering our recent setbacks,
我認為我們做得還不錯
I think we're doing pretty good.
你們應該感到自豪 來吧
You should be proud. Come on.
來吧 夥計們 來吧 來吧 來吧
Come on, guys. Come on. Come on.
但真正的比賽現在才開始
But the ball game starts now.
我們正在加強安保 所以商店是安全的
We're beefing up security so the store is safe
家庭在店裏感到安全
and families feel safe in the store.
完全按計劃進行
Right on schedule.
因為如果我們的顧客過個好聖誕節
Because if our customers have a good Christmas,
我們也能過好
then so do we.
你真準時 我的朋友 我喜歡
You are so punctual, my friend. I like it.
你的工作是賣玩具
Your job is to sell toys.
這次會稍微重一點
It's gonna be a little bit heavier this time around.
是的 最近收到很多這種
Yeah, getting a lot of these lately.
對你的手臂肌肉有好處
It's good for your arms, muscles there.
我們會提早開門
We're gonna open early
在這個聖誕季每天營業到很晚
and stay open late every day this Christmas season,
包括平安夜
and that includes Christmas Eve.
我貼出了新的排班表
I posted the new schedule.
現在 我知道你們中的一些人
Now, I know some of you
會有不想上的班次
are gonna have shifts they don't want,
但沒有例外或更改
but there's no exceptions or changes.
排班表上有你的名字你就得來上班
You show up when your name is on the schedule.
現在 讓我們過一個快樂的聖誕節
Now, let's have a happy Christmas.
讓我們為了孩子們努力
Let's do this for the kids.
來吧 回去工作
Come on. Back to work.
哦 我們的天父是馬利亞的創造者
Oh, our Father is The maker of Mary
馬利亞是他兒子的母親
And Mary is The mother of his Son
兒子是天父的祝福
The Son is a blessing From the Father
所以讓我們聽見感謝和讚美
So let's hear Thanks and praise
唱聖誕快樂
Sing happy Christmas
給你
To you
你
You...
帽子不錯
Nice hat.
你看起來像個聖誕超級反派
You look like a Christmas supervillain.
是的 我是個聖誕超級反派
Yeah, I am a Christmas supervillain.
不過你來開車
You're driving, though.
我開車 你來開
I'm driving? You are driving.
好的
Okay.
天啊 你買了這麼多東西
Holy shit, you got so much stuff.
媽媽會嚇壞的
Mom's gonna freak out.
是的 她會高興得嚇壞的
Yeah, she's gonna freak out with joy.
為每個人回來
Coming back for everyone
聖誕節再次來臨
Christmas is coming back again...
嗨 媽媽 嗨 媽媽
Hi, Mom. Hi, Mom.
好的
Okay.
時間正好
Perfect timing.
大家都準備好要走了
Everyone's ready to go.
啵
Mwah.
嘿 孩子們
Hey, guys.
我今晚不能去教堂了 為什麼
I can't go to church tonight. Why not?
我必須超級早起
I have to wake up super early.
我明天有班
I have a shift tomorrow.
那我有個好消息告訴你
Then I have good news for you.
米奇打電話來了 他會當個好人
Mitch called, and he's gonna be a nice guy
讓你睡個懶覺
and let you sleep in.
米奇打電話來了 嗯哼 是的
Mitch called? Mm-hmm. Yeah.
說是十點半
Uh, said 10:30.
十點半 是的
10:30?  Yeah.
十點半到四點半 我想他是這麼說的
10:30 to 4:30, I think he said.
為什麼
Why?
我 呃 我不知道
I, uh... I don't know.
我是說 也許他知道你有家庭
I mean, maybe he knows that you have a family
他想讓你能和家人一起過節
and he wants you to be able to spend the holidays with them.
為每個人回來
Coming back For everyone...
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
嘿 媽媽 嘿
Hey, Mom. Hey.
我愛你 我愛你
I love you. I love you.
我愛你
I love you.
到馬槽裏來
Come on into the manger.
她說沒有地方
Well, she said There was no room
沒有地方 沒有地方
No room No room
客棧裏沒有空房
No room at the inn
嗯 嗯 時候已經完全到了
Well, well The time had fully come
救主降生的時候
For the Savior To be born
但他們告訴她沒有地方
But they told her There was no room
沒有空房 沒有空房
No roomNo room
旅店沒有空房
No room at the inn
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey
根據聖言 哦 是的
According to the WordOh, yes
曾有一位處女
There was a virgin girl
嘿 嘿 哦 是的
Hey, heyOh, yes
耶穌之母 哦 是的
Mother of JesusOh, yes
那夜四處徘徊 哦 是的
Wandering round that nightOh, yes
她努力尋找一個地方
She was trying<i>To find a place
讓救世主降臨
For the Savior to be born
但他們告訴她沒有空房
But they told her<i>There was no room
沒有空房 沒有空房
No roomNo room
旅店沒有空房
No room at the inn
我說沒有空房
I said there was no room
沒有空房 沒有空房
No roomNo room
旅店沒有空房
No room at the inn
再說一次沒有空房
One more time<i>There was no room
沒有空房 沒有空房
No roomNo room
旅店沒有空房
No room at the inn
我說時機已完全成熟
I said the time<i>Had fully come
救世主即將降臨
For the Savior To be born...
奧蒂斯回去工作 快來 清理一下育嬰室好嗎
Otis, back to work. Come on. Clean that nursery, would you?
就像我吩咐你的那樣 好的
Like I told you to. Okay.
你好先生 你好
<i>Hello, sir.<i>Hello.</i>
錢先生 錢先生
Mr. Money Man, Mr. Money Man.
聽那雪橇鈴鐺響叮噹
Just hear those<i>Sleigh bells jingling...
早上好玩具反斗城的員工們
Good morning, Toys "R" Us employees!
你好 我們是警察
Hello. This is the police.
你們知道後面有警報器在響嗎
You guys, you know you got an alarm going off back there?
大家往這邊走
Everybody, this way.
你跟我來 走快一點
You're coming with me. Little faster.
天啊 天啊 他有槍
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. He has a gun.
嘿 嘿 嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
請把你的手從槍上拿開先生
Please keep your hand away from your gun, sir.
趴下 趴在地上
Get on, get on your stomach.
你們兩個 過來
You two, come here.
只要大家按我說的做就不會有人受傷
No one's gonna get hurt if everybody just does what I say.
趴在地上 奧蒂斯過來
On your stomach. Otis, here.
把大家都綁起來
Zip-tie everybody up.
奧蒂斯快點 呃
Otis, come on. Uh...
老天 米奇把大家都綁起來
Jesus Christ. Mitch, zip-tie everybody up.
好嗎 趴下 眼睛看地上
Okay? Get on your stomachs, eyes down.
好的 我說了什麼
Okay. Wh-What did I say?
快點 趴下
Come on. On your stomach.
趴下
Get down.
現在別這樣
Don't do this right now.
嘿 嘿
Hey, hey.
我說了什麼
What did I say?
該死
Shit.
那不是我的錯
That wasn't my fault.
他聽不懂人話
He's a bad listener.
這不可能
This is not happening.
大家深呼吸
Everybody, take a breath.
米奇給我一個
Mitch, give me one of those.
謝謝你先生
Thank you, sir.
對不起 對不起
Sorry. Sorry.
好的
Okay.
對不起 對不起 快點米奇
Sorry. Sorry. Come on, Mitch.
動作快點 快走
Let's get a hop on. Let's go.
會沒事的 對不起 對不起
It's gonna be okay. Sorry. Sorry.
各位
Guys.
大家冷靜點 我很抱歉
Everybody, just calm down. I'm sorry about this.
米奇拿鑰匙 快點
Mitch, get the keys. Come on.
我們去保險櫃 不這裏沒錢
Let's go to the safe. No, there's no money here.
沒有保險櫃 你以為我不知道
There's no safe. You think I don't know
你們每週二都會把存款送去銀行嗎
that there's a deposit that you take to the bank every Tuesday?
嗯 拜託了快點
Huh? Come on, please.
你沒事的
You're okay.
眼睛看下面 眼睛看下面
Eyes down. Eyes down.
對不起各位 馬上就結束了
I'm sorry about this, guys. It'll be all over in a second.
快點 你每天都做這個 冷靜點
Come on. You do this every day. Calm down.
來吧 開始 幹得好
Come on. Here we go. Good job.
眼睛看下面
Eyes down.
只要找到鑰匙
Just... find the key.
天啊
Oh, God.
外面的人眼睛看下面
Eyes down out there!
好的 放進去
Yes. Okay, put it in.
哦 好的 放進保險櫃然後打開
Oh. Okay. Put it in the safe and open it.
把袋子拿出來 放下
Take the bag out. Put it down.
我需要你把墨彈拿出來
I need you to take the ink bomb out.
如果我那麼做墨汁會噴得到處都是
If I do that, it'll blow up everywhere.
如果你動作快就不會
Not if you do it quick.
馬上再拉上明白嗎
Zip it right back up really fast, okay?
好的
Okay.
好的 很好
Okay, good.
天啊
Oh, God.
真該死
Goddamn it.
他需要救護車
He needs an ambulance!
你說過不會傷害任何人但你傷了他
You said you weren't gonna hurt anyone, but you hurt him!
他需要救護車
He needs an ambulance!
你就是個惡霸
And you're just a bully!
You're just a bully!
奧蒂斯
Otis?
來吧 虔誠的信徒們
O come, all ye faithful
我看不見了
I can't see.
他需要他需要救護車
He need... he needs an ambulance.
歡欣而鼓舞
Joyful and triumphant...
看來很明顯我就是個軟柿子對吧
I guess it's obvious I'm just a pushover, huh?
好吧奧蒂斯 我這就打911好嗎
All right, Otis. Fine, I'm calling 911, okay?
前往伯利恆
To Bethlehem
來瞻仰他
Come and behold him
這裏是911 有什麼緊急情況
<i>911. What's your emergency?</i>
天使之王已降生
Born the king of angels
來吧 讓我們
O come, let us
崇拜他 該死
Adore himShit.
來吧 讓我們崇拜他
O come Let us adore him
來吧 讓我們 該死
O come, let usShit!
崇拜他
Adore him
基督我主
Christ the Lord
歌唱
Sing...
夏洛特警察 夏洛特警察
Charlotte Police! Charlotte Police!
警察局
Police department!
夏洛特警察 夏洛特警察
Charlotte Police! Charlotte Police!
歡欣歌唱
Sing in exultation
哦 哦 哇 好的 等一下
Oh, oh, wow. Okay. Wait a second.
歌唱 所有公民們
Sing, all ye citizens...
你剛才在罵他
You were calling him names.
他拿著槍
He had a gun,
他還罵他是惡霸
and he was calling him a bully.
天啊
Oh, man.
榮耀歸於上帝
Glory to God
至高無上 榮耀
In the highest, glory
來吧 讓我們崇拜他
O come<i>Let us adore him...
你看到他任何皮膚
<i>Did you see<i>any part of his skin</i>
或其他衣物了嗎
<i>or any other clothing?</i>
嗯 我能看出他是個白人 是的
<i>Um, I could tell<i>he was a white man, yeah.</i>
你看到他的眼睛了嗎
Did you see his eyes?
沒有
Mm-mm.
這真是太棒了傑夫
This is fucking fantastic, Jeff.
你真是個瘋子知道嗎
You a fucking nut, you know that?
太棒了 寶貝你看到了嗎
It's fucking great. Baby, you see this?
看到了
Yeah.
好的 我們看看
Okay, let's see.
這是你北卡羅來納州簽發的駕照對吧
This is your North Carolina-issued driver's license, all right?
那是你的護照 公證過的出生證明
That's your passport. Notarized birth certificate.
這是你上一份工作的工資單存根
You got your check stubs from your last job.
哦 這是你的機票
Oh, and there is your ticket.
你晚上11點從夏洛特起飛
You leave at 11:00 p.m. out of Charlotte.
你需要在邁阿密轉機
Now, what you're gonna do is a layover in Miami,
然後飛往巴蘭基亞
and then you're gonna fly to Barranquilla.
從那裏你再坐一小段巴士
From there, you're gonna take a little bus
週末前就能到達委內瑞拉
and it'll have you in Venezuela before the weekend's out.
看來我需要的都齊了
Looks like I got everything I need
萬一我決定明天走
in case I decide to go tomorrow.
決定
"Decide"?
你已經做了決定老兄
You already made your decision, man.
你在說什麼
What you talking about?
你總不能指望我聖誕節走吧
I mean, you can't expect me to go on Christmas, right?
我就不能多待一陣嗎 我會低調行事的
Can't I just stay awhile? I'll just lay low.
你沒得選傑夫
That's not a choice you have, Jeff.
你明天必須走
You got to leave tomorrow.
我有人在那接應你老兄
I got people waiting on you, man.
我在邁阿密有個安保人員
I got a security guy in Miami.
他會在三號隊伍那裏
He'll be at line three.
你只有一次機會老兄 明晚11點
You got one shot, man. 11:00 p.m. tomorrow.
別錯過這次機會 明白嗎
Don't miss this shot. All right?
寶貝給他戴上假髮
Baby, let's get this, uh, wig on him.
沒問題
You bet.
還有件事我在想
One more thing I was thinking about.
電視上看到有個持械搶劫的新聞
Saw on the TV there was some shit about a armed robbery.
我對此一無所知
I don't know nothing about that.
我需要你的拇指
I need your thumbs.
你知道你得掩蓋行蹤傑夫
You know, you got to cover your tracks, Jeff.
是的 所有你接觸過的東西
Yeah. Everything you touch.
我需要你仔細想想你和誰說過話
I need you to really think about who you talked to,
誰和你說過話 誰知道你的聲音
who talked to you, who knows your voice.
我為你可是冒了大險 你明白的對吧
I'm over a cliff for you, man. You understand that, right?
明白
Yeah.
所以 沒有嗎
So, nothing?
沒有看過醫生
No doctor's visits?
呃 我去看了牙醫補了幾顆牙
Uh, I went to the dentist and got some cavities filled.
但就這個
But that's it.
好的 沒拍X光片嗎
Okay. You ain't get no X-rays?
拍了X光片 但我用了假名
No, I got X-rays, but I gave 'em a fake name.
好吧 但這其實沒什麼用
Okay. Well, it don't really matter
如果你用了假名但他們有你的牙科記錄傑夫
if you gave 'em a fake name if they got your teeth, Jeff.
好吧 是的
All right. Yeah.
聽著 我會處理好的
Look, I'll take care of it.
你搞出的爛攤子你自己收拾乾淨
Any messes you made, you clean it up.
然後你直接去機場
Then you go straight to the airport
等著你的航班
and wait for your flight.
別上新聞
No getting on the news.
別跟你打過招呼的人道別
No good-byes to anyone you said hello to.
意思就是沒有明信片沒有電話什麼都沒有
That means no postcards, no calls. No none of that.
靠 我們合作得挺愉快的
Shit, we had a good run.
你知道嗎
You know?
你知道等這些事情平息下來之後
You know, after all this stuff calms down and, like,
我在那邊安頓好了
I get settled over there,
你覺得你能告訴一些人我在哪裏
do you think you could tell some people where I'm at
他們也許能有時來看看我嗎
and they maybe could... visit me sometime?
不不不
No, no, no.
沒那種事老兄
It's none of that, man.
沒人會來看你傑夫
Nobody coming to see you, Jeff.
你要重新開始
You're starting over.
現在你只能靠自己了
You're on your own now.
是的
Yeah.
哎呀
Oops.
喂
Hello?
約翰
<i>John.</i>
我正想打給你
I was just about to call you.
一切都好嗎
Is everything okay?
我一直在打給你
<i>I've been calling you.</i>
你在哪裏
<i>Where are you?</i>
我在開車
I'm driving.
其實我剛靠邊停下
Well, actually, I just pulled over.
你來吃聖誕晚餐嗎
<i>Are you coming to Christmas dinner?</i>
女兒們一直在問你
<i>The girls have been asking for you.</i>
來的 當然來
Yeah. Yeah, of course.
是的 我不會錯過的
Yeah, I wouldn't miss it.
五點見面好嗎
<i>Want to meet us at 5:00?</i>
在家
<i>At home?</i>
五點 好的 聽起來不錯
At 5:00? Yeah, yeah, that sounds good.
好的 我會到的
Yeah. I'll be there.
你在聽嗎 你沒事吧
You there? Are you okay?
我能聽到你 我能聽到你的呼吸聲
I can hear you, I can hear you breathing.
我愛你約翰
<i>I love you, John.</i>
我也愛你莉
I love you, too, Leigh.
五點見
<i>I'll see you at 5:00.</i>
莉
Leigh?
聖誕快樂
Merry Christmas...
警察 趴下
Police! Lay down!
趴到地上 趴下
Get on the ground! Get down!
趴到地上 趴到地上
Get on the ground! Get on the ground!
趴下 趴下 趴下
On the ground! Get down. Get down.
別動
Don't move.
別動 不許動
Don't move. Do not move.
很好 別動
Doing good. Don't move.
照我們說的做你就不會受傷 明白嗎
Do as we say and you won't get hurt. You understand me?
我抓住他了 別動
I got him. Nuh-uh.
別動 混蛋
Don't move, dickhead.
他媽的不許動 戲演完了
Don't fucking move. Drama's over.
你叫什麼名字
What's your name?
<i>What's your name?</i>
我想你知道我的名字
<i>I think you know my name.</i>
你叫什麼名字
<i>What's your name?</i>
傑弗裏曼徹斯特
<i>Jeffrey Manchester.</i>
身份確認 目標 我們抓住他了
<i>PID. Target.<i>We got him.</i>
我們抓到屋頂人了
<i>We got the Roofman.</i>
他差點就成功了
<i>He almost made it.</i>
我們走
<i>Let's move.</i>
快點
Come on.
搜他身 他是個狡猾的傢伙
Search his ass. He's a tricky motherfucker.
這邊 過來
This way. Come here.
仔細搜
Search him good.
我可能是故意讓自己被抓的
<i>I probably let myself get caught.</i>
或者也許我只是無法不告而別
<i>Or maybe I just couldn't leave without saying goodbye.</i>
他們重判了我
<i>They threw the book at me.</i>
加判了384個月
<i>Gave me 384 more months.</i>
這意味著等我從這裏出去時
<i>That means by the time I get out of here,</i>
我已經是個老頭了
<i>I'll be an old man.</i>
這讓我有很多時間思考我的人生
<i>Gave me a lot of time to think about my life.</i>
所有一切
<i>Everything.</i>
當我在外面的世界時
<i>When I was out there in the world,</i>
我沒有想過那些我危及到的
<i>I wasn't thinking of the things</i>
事物或人們
<i>or people that I was putting at risk.</i>
而現在我滿腦子都是這些
<i>Now that's all I think about.</i>
我們都喜歡回到過去想像
<i>We all like to go back in time to imagine</i>
如果我們做出不同的選擇
<i>how things could've gone differently</i>
事情會如何不同
<i>if we made different choices.</i>
就像現在
<i>Like right now.</i>
我在想像如果我從沒犯下那些罪行
<i>I was imagining what it would've been like</i>
失去我的家人會是什麼樣子
<i>if I never committed all those crimes</i>
會是什麼樣子
<i>and lost my family.</i>
或者如果我能繼續
<i>Or if I got to keep on living</i>
和莉以及她的女兒們永遠生活在一起
<i>with Leigh and her girls forever.</i>
當然她們會稍微使喚我一下
<i>Sure, they'd boss me around a little</i>
逼我去教堂
<i>and make me go to church.</i>
但她們會笑我愚蠢的笑話並原諒我
<i>But they'd laugh at my dumb jokes and forgive me</i>
當我過於冷酷和算計的時候
<i>when I was on the wrong part of cold and calculating.</i>
諸如此類
<i>Or something.</i>
我開始意識到所有我愛的人
<i>I started to realize that all those people I loved</i>
並不需要我給他們那麼多東西
<i>didn't need me to give them so many things.</i>
他們需要的只是我
<i>They just needed me.</i>
我的時間
<i>My time.</i>
而現在我只有時間了
<i>And now that's all I have.</i>
時間 我拿了四個A
<i>Time. <i>I got four A's.</i>
你全拿了A
You got all A's?
是的
<i>Yeah.</i>
連數學也是 是的
Even in math? <i>Yeah.</i>
貝基我真為你驕傲
Becky, I'm so proud of you.
事情本可以有不同的走向毫無疑問
<i>It all could've gone a different way, for sure.</i>
但它沒有 它走上了這條路
<i>But it didn't. It went this way.</i>
嘿夥計
Hey, buddy.
而這樣我也能接受
<i>And that was okay with me.</i>
因為在這裏我
'Cause in here, I...
我再也不會傷害任何人了
I can't hurt anybody anymore.
是的 我
Yeah. I'm...
我就在我該在的地方
I'm where I'm supposed to be.
你想過嗎
You ever think about it?
什麼
What?
你知道的 從這地方越獄
You know, breaking out of this place.
不 不 嗯
No. No. Mm.
我
I'm...
這裏現在是我的家了
This is my home now.
你知道嗎我必須承認兄弟
You know, I have to admit, brother, like,
那個愛情故事部分真的很棒
that love story part was really good.
我很好奇 你後來再見過莉嗎
I am curious. You ever see Leigh again?
嘿 嗨
Hey. Hi.
我該叫你傑弗裏嗎
Should I call you Jeffrey?
就當是你生命中另一個混蛋傑弗裏吧 是的
Just another jerk Jeffrey in your life, I guess. Yeah.
林賽和迪怎麼樣了
How's Lindsay and Dee?
她們還好
They're okay.
是的
Yeah.
迪還留著劉海嗎
Did Dee keep her bangs?
留著
She did.
是的
Yeah.
對不起
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉我傷害了你
I'm so sorry that I hurt you.
我很抱歉我沒能保護你
I'm sorry I couldn't protect you.
你沒什麼需要道歉的莉
You don't have anything to be sorry about, Leigh.
你沒有
You don't.
你沒有傷害任何人
You didn't hurt anybody.
你只是說出了真相
You just told the truth.
是的
Yeah.
我曾經非常生你的氣
I was really angry at you.
我最生氣的是你傷害了女兒們
I was most angry at how you hurt the girls.
但現在我不那麼想了
But that's not the way I think about it now.
好嗎
Okay?
我把它看作一場冒險
I think about it as an adventure.
我們有過很多歡樂時光
We had a lot of fun.
我們心存感激
We're thankful.
那麼
Well...
也許我以後會來看你
Maybe I'll come visit you sometime.
敲我的窗戶嗎
Gonna tap on my window?
也許我會直接敲門
Maybe I'll just knock on the door.
屋頂人再次歸來犯案
<i>The Roofman<i>has returned to rob again,</i>
昨夜他切穿屋頂進入這家
<i>overnight cutting his way into this McDonald's</i>
位於威爾金森和梅恩街交叉路口的麥當勞
<i>on the intersection of Wilkinson and Main.</i>
看看他的作案手法
Just to look at what he's done,
他顯得非常聰明
it appears he's very intelligent.
只是他也喜歡犯罪
Um, it's just that he also likes to commit crime.
切穿屋頂
<i>Holes cut into the roofs,</i>
讓員工進入冷藏庫
<i>workers told to get into the coolers,</i>
但無人受傷
<i>but no one was hurt.</i>
事實上嫌疑人很友善
<i>In fact, the suspect was nice.</i>
非常有禮貌的人
Very polite person.
他總是確保員工
He always makes sure that the employees,
在他帶他們進冷藏庫之前
before he walked them into the refrigerator,
讓他們穿上外套
that he has them put on their coats
這樣他們能保暖
so that they'll stay warm.
這是早些時候的屋頂人合成畫像
<i>This was an earlier composite drawing of Roofman,</i>
他總是戴著面具
<i>always wearing a mask.</i>
這裏的店主拒絕評論
<i>The owner here refused to comment</i>
搶劫案的所有細節
<i>on all details of the robbery,</i>
讓聯繫麥當勞公司
<i>referring calls to the McDonald's corporation.</i>
他還搶劫過漢堡王和百視達
<i>But he's also robbed Burger King and Blockbuster...</i>
警方抓獲他時他身上有9000美元現金
<i>Police caught him<i>with $9,000 in cash,</i>
據稱是從兩家麥當勞餐廳偷來的
<i>allegedly stolen from two McDonald's restaurants,</i>
第一家加斯托尼亞第二家貝爾蒙特
<i>the first in Gastonia, the second in Belmont.</i>
嫌疑人差點逃脫
<i>The suspect almost got away,</i>
直到貝爾蒙特這家麥當勞的一名員工
<i>until a worker at this Belmont McDonald's</i>
看到他逃跑的方向並報警
<i>saw which way he ran and then called police.</i>
我在貝爾蒙特麥當勞搶劫案中與傑弗裏有過接觸
I interacted with Jeffrey on the robbery that happened in the McDonald's in Belmont.
他一直在說
<i>The whole time, he was saying,</i>
我很抱歉 你們是好人
<i>"I'm so sorry. You guys are the good people.</i>
我是壞人
<i>I'm the bad person."</i>
他是個不錯的傢伙
He was a nice fella.
他 他非常友善
He, uh, he was real nice.
他沒有 他沒有表現得像
He didn't, uh... he didn't come across as, uh...
你知道 過來罵罵咧咧那種
you know, come up, talk junk, you know.
或者問我為什麼在這裏 沒有那種事
Or, "Why am I here?" Nothing like that.
你知道 他 他是個不錯的傢伙
You know, he... he was a nice fella.
他是個厲害的騙子
He's an incredible liar,
幾乎在所有事情上都是
um, pretty much about everything.
大家都覺得哦他真是個英雄
Everybody thinks, "Oh, he's such a hero"
因為他把玩具給了孩子們
"because he-he gave the toys to the children."
但那些玩具是偷來的
Well, the toys are stolen.
至於說是否曾有過一絲
As far as, like, having an inkling
覺得可能有點問題
to maybe there's something there,
不我沒有任何預感
no, I didn't have any kind of inkling.
他是個不錯的傢伙 他加入了我們的教會
He was a nice fella. He got involved in our church.
但現在牧師知道了
<i>But now that the pastor knows.</i>
約翰其實是傑弗裏曼徹斯特
<i>John is really Jeffrey Manchester,</i>
那個搶劫玩具反斗城並縱火燒燬牙醫診所的逃犯
<i>the escaped convict accused of sticking up Toys "R" Us</i>
他作何感想
<i>and torching a dentist's office, how does he feel?</i>
我的信念是
My belief is that, um,
作為一個教會你必須支持某個人
as a church, you got to stand with somebody.
這不意味著你認同他們的所作所為
Doesn't mean that you agree with what they did.
屋頂人或天台劫匪
The Roofman, or the Rooftop Robber,
我從未聽說過任何相關消息
I-I never heard anything about that.
那是 我對一切都不知情
It was... I was oblivious to anything
直到我和傑弗裏的關係結束後
until after my relationship with Jeffrey,
然後他被捕了
and then he was captured.
之後似乎到處都在報道
Then it just seemed to be everywhere.
從沒想過我的診所會發生這種事
Never thought that would happen to my office,
他試圖放火燒了它來掩蓋他的記錄
him trying to burn it down to-to hide his record.
整個前台區域都燒沒了
The whole front area was gone.
起初在我看來
In the beginning, it just seemed to me
他一切都很完美
he had everything together.
這是一個完美的例子說明貪婪金錢
And it's a perfect example of how greed and money
以及生活中的不良影響會改變你的結局
and bad influences in your life could change your outcome.
史密斯牧師說
<i>Pastor Smith says</i>
他已經去監獄探望過曼徹斯特
<i>he's already visited Manchester in jail.</i>
他不敢相信我去看他了
He could not believe that I came to see him,
我們不會只是對他非常生氣
that, um, that we would not just be really mad at him
然後對他置之不理
and turn our back on him.
儘管是一名教會成員
<i>Although it was a church member</i>
舉報了曼徹斯特
<i>who turned Manchester in.</i>
警方抓獲他時
<i>Police captured him</i>
他正離開萊恩斯科特的公寓
<i>leaving the apartment of Leigh Wainscott,</i>
他在教會單身活動中認識的新女友
<i>the new girlfriend he met at a church singles event.</i>
我和我的大女兒談過這個 你知道
I talked to my oldest daughter, you know, about this,
最近 我問她
um, recently, and, uh, I asked her
和我分享她記得的任何事情
to share with me anything that she remembered,
任何她能分享的 她只是說
um, that she could share, and she just said,
哦是的我記得很清楚
"Oh, yeah, I remember very well.
他他太棒了你知道
"He was, he was awesome, you know."
我們玩得很開心
"We had so much fun."
而且
And, um...
她們對他沒有任何負面評價
They didn't have anything bad to say about him.
一點也沒有
Nothing at all.